Hey. Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Ask
Kabijit show this is episode 345 and we
are discussing what's going on in the
war against Iran the US Israeli war
against Iran that's what we're going to
discuss today and other things as well
as per your as per your questions I'll
take question from you from the super
chat as many as possible today and
before we do that let's see who all is
there in the live chat with us I can see
Sona Sanduji Hersh Patel Raman Gil Ritik
Pawar Mandar Kerkar Pratarana
Geopolitical Dubai from Indor good to
see you sir. Mayul Rajes Babu from
Kerala good to have you. Dashan Patel
from Dip Kerala Mojour. Nirvana Shanks
son how are you doing? Uh Janesh hello
Nira Bardaja.
Good evening Laran
good evening. SKR7733
good evening are Singh J. Yes. Hello.
Uh, real Radi Putin says, "Is lockdown
inevitable?" We shall discuss that.
Shrih Hari Arun namaste.
Alkashikari, namaste. Arun 211093. Ryan
KC.
Uh, Aran Shawan from the UK. Good to
have you, sir. Uh, P. Sudhir Kumar PSK.
Happy birthday to you. P. Sudhir Kumar
PSK. Um, Vensh Achara SKR Dundu. I
haven't seen it yet. I haven't seen it
yet. Uh
um
peumar once again happy birthday once
again live
that's all right okayishuk
live says sense your frustrations at
major general raj no look it's okay uh
yes I did this podcast with major
general rajim narayan gi sir uh on the
aaram musafer podcast you know as as is
natural no two people can agree on
everything which is perfectly Fine. Uh,
Anu Anush Sharma Photography. Namaskar.
Um, who else do we have? Who else do we
have? S. Morgan. Hello. Hello. Swami.
Hello. Swami from Jaipur. I think. Yes.
Nodita Varma. Namaskar. Sesh. Nali. YT.
Shishir. Padya.
Sangeita. Anthony. Hello. Sesh. Nali.
Once again. Who else do we have? Who
else do we have? Bin Salman. Hello. Bin
Salman. Heisenberg. Hello. Priyanasud.
SP Arush. Hello. really now Patel.
Namaste ma'am. Geopolitical way from
Indor once again. Um Sam Shukla hello uh
G H O T O U Ram Ram Sergi Shubham
Harapan guy from Maharo. Hello Shbam. Uh
who else? Vikash Vikas Mishra 7
S7 E Vinod Somi from Jaipur Obear hello
good to have you GU 75 Anu from the US.
Uh good to see you. Good morning. Hi
Shirinat NC Penguin. Hello. Uh Sabraat
Tukla.
Um who has watched me over a thousand
hours? Well, that's incredible. Thank
you so much. Thank you so much. It's
genuinely a privilege. Thank you indeed.
Swami says, "Have I watched Casablanca?"
Yes, I've watched Casablanca. Yes, I
have. Uh Dasura 73821, etc. Hello Pis
Kumar Tesh Pandi Arian Khal 673 Muk
Mukshiidi
Nitan Sharma real
uh everybody else I won't be able to
greet you all Danu Nahapana is here well
nahana namaste okay so before I get into
the Q&As's let's examine what's happened
since the last time we had a chat we we
had this this live stream right the last
one was this last Sunday, wasn't it? So,
what's happened? So, President Trump,
the American President Shri Donald Trump
G uh gave uh an address to the nation
early morning today, right? 6:30 a.m. or
so India time
and uh the whole world was waiting to
hear what Mr. Donald Trump would have to
say about this. Is it going to people
were wondering is he going to end the
war? Is he going to announce a
ceasefire? Is he going to announce an
escalation? Is he going to announce that
he's withdrawing from NATO? I was on
Republic TV yesterday 8 p.m. with Arnab
Gowami and that's what we were
discussing. That's what Arnab was
wondering about. That's what everyone
was wondering about that what is Trump
going to speak about.
Right?
So um so Mr. Trump gave his speech his
address to the nation. It was like 15 20
minutes right and nothing new nothing at
all. It's like he was repeating what he
had tweeted in the past,
right?
And absolutely nothing in it. He tried
to justify his war against Iran. He's
has always said that he is winning. It's
going to take like two, three weeks
more. I I don't know two weeks, three
weeks more. And his secretary of war,
Pete Hegsith, said that they're going to
bomb Iran back to the stoage. I think
Trump also said that in this in the
speech and uh yeah so the war goes on I
suppose the war goes on he has made so
many flip-flops Donald Trump over the
past month so many flip flip-flops in
terms of the objectives of the war
so it doesn't look like this war is any
ending anytime soon
so let's let's take a look at as always
a few u you know a few tweets that will
help us understand what's going on. So
this is from today morning breaking.
President Donald Trump of the US says
that the US will leave Iran within two
weeks, maybe 3 weeks. That's stretching
the White House's initial guidance of
four to six weeks weeks war. So clearly
it's overstretching the budget or the
time allocation that they had in mind
earlier.
When they started the war, I think they
were uh they were laboring under the
delusion that the war will be over in 48
hours. But clearly that's not happened.
Uh so that's about Trump. This is from a
tweet from the White House. For years,
everyone has said that Iran cannot have
nuclear weapons. But in the end, those
are just words if you're not willing to
take action when the time comes. So
Trump is taking action. It's not just
words with Trump. It's all actions
according to him. Let's see what actions
he's able to take about Iran and nuclear
weapons.
Now you have Pete Hexet, the Secretary
of War, who says back to the storage. So
they are promising that they're going to
bomb Iran back to the stone age. What
happened to liberating the people of
Iran?
Wasn't the agenda allegedly to liberate
the people of Iran from this horrible
regime of the Ayatollas?
So if you're going to bomb that nation
back to the stone age, if you're going
to destroy schools with children in it,
if you're going to bomb universities,
how how how exactly are you liberating
the people? It's not about liberation
then, right? Trump seems to be very
gleefully talking about bombing Iran
back to the stone age and this guy Hath
back to the stone age. So they are
promising they're going to send Iran
back to the stone age. They're going to
bomb the hell out of Iran over the next
2 3 4 weeks. That's what they are
promising.
And yet they are not able. They're not
able to force Iran to open the state of
Hormuz. Trump is pleading to the
Europeans and other nations that you
know what you need to come in and open
the state of Hormos if you want the oil
because we Americans we have our own oil
but it's you Europeans and you other
nations who want oil from the state of
Hormos so you need to come in and force
Iran to open it which means he wants to
drag more nations into the war and
that's where we start talking about
something very bad which is World War II
so that's by Pete Hexet now what do we
have yeah this This is again from ear
earlier today. President Trump of the US
says that the US is going to hit Iran
extremely hard over the next 2 three
weeks. We're going to bring them back to
the stone ages. He seems to be very
pleased about bombing a nation to the
stone age. Right. So that's his promise.
Let's see how that goes. What else? Uh
this is from yesterday. US President
Donald Trump threatens to halt weapons
supplies to Ukraine unless European
countries agree to agree to join a
coalition to secure the straight of
Hormos. Right? So once again, he is
issuing threats that I'm going to stop
weapons supplies to Ukraine unless
European nations join a coalition to
secure essentially to to to fight
against Iran in the Persian Gulf region,
the the the Arabian Sea region, the
Straight of Hormos region and force Iran
to open the Straight of Hormos. Does
Trump imagine that if the US with its
aircraft carriers and its military might
was unable to force Iran to open the
state of does he imagine that the
European nations will be able to make
this happen? It's impossible. If the US
can't do it, the Europeans simply
certainly can't do it. So Trump just
wants more nations to join the war. He
seems to be intent on dragging the world
into World War II
because if more European nations join in
then I suppose China and Russia will
have a very very good incentive very
strong incentive to join in more more
actively than what they are doing right
now.
Uh okay what else? Congress so this is a
tweet this is a piece of news from 2023.
See, Trump has been complaining about
NATO, hasn't he? Trump has been
complaining about NATO.
What's happened is that there's a bunch
of NATO nations that have refused to
give the United States
permission to use military bases in
those nations
as as part of the war against Iran. And
they have also refused to allow their
airspace to be used by the US in
connection with the war against Iran.
Which nations are these? Well, you have
Italy, you have France, you have Spain,
you have Poland, you have Greece, and
I'm sure there's more nations. So all
these nations have refused permission to
the US to use their airspace or their
military bases as as staging posts or
transit areas for uh participating in
the war against Iran. So Trump is
extremely upset about this matter.
Uh let me try and find some more tweet
tweets. I'm sure there is something
more. Give me a second.
So,
so yeah, the the the Americans are
extremely upset with the Europeans that
they are, you know, not not behaving
like good nice vasals.
Okay, let me let me put up a couple more
tweets here. Give me a second.
Um,
there's one more here.
And there's one more here.
Okay, that's going to load. And another
one is going to load. Okay.
So, what have we here? So, this is uh a
tweet from the White House. Is it from
the White House? No, it's from the
Department of State.
Uh Secretary,
please be silent, sir. Okay. So,
Secretary Rubio says, "Why are we in
NATO?" You have to ask that question.
Why is the United States in NATO? You
have to ask that question. Why does the
US send trillions of dollars and have
all of these American forces stationed
in the region when in America's time of
need, the US is not allowed to use those
bases? That is the question he's asking.
Well, you know, Mr. Rubio, the United
States pays for the privilege of
occupying Europe militarily
and projecting power all the way up to
Russia's doorstep. So the US is getting
that incredible access all across
Western Europe. It's able to put bombs,
weapons, arms, ammunition, missiles,
nuclear weapons right at Russia's
doorstep because it is part of NATO.
So shouldn't the US pay for the
privilege, right? And in exchange for
that, NATO nations, they purchase
American weapons and Trump has already
forced the NATO nations to double their
contribution to the alliance by 2030 and
they have agreed, right? So the question
is why are the Americans complaining?
I mean, according to the NATO charter,
the NATO nations aren't under any
obligation to allow America access to
their bases and their airspace to fight
a war that does not involve NATO in any
shape or form. Right? So, uh that's what
the Americans uh are complaining about.
Right? That's what they're complaining
about. Uh now, we have this interesting
tweet from um Ed Davyy. He's the leader
of the Liberal Democrats uh in the UK.
It's it's a political party in the UK.
Here's what he says. He says that Trump
wants to rip up NATO because the UK
refuses to be dragged into this is this
illegal war. And the other NATO nations
refuse to be dragged into this illegal
war. And then he says very something
very interesting. Threats to NATO today
become threats to Trident tomorrow.
The UK can't rely on Trump for UK's
national security. Britain needs a truly
independent nuclear deterrent committed
to NATO defense. So here's the deal. The
UK Britain has a number of nuclear
submarines and these nuclear submarines
are part of UK's nuclear deterrent. The
UK has a number of nuclear warheads.
Okay. And these warheads they are mated
to these trident missiles ballistic
missiles that are placed inside these
submarines. Now the trident missiles are
American missiles.
Okay. So British bombs are mated to
American missiles that are placed inside
British submarines. But the missiles are
American. You see Britain doesn't have
missiles of its own. It was made to
dismantle its rocket program, space
program, missile program decades ago.
So they don't have their own missiles.
These are American missiles. And guess
who has the big red button? On whose
desk does the big red button sit? Does
it sit on the desk of Mr. Kir Starmer in
10 Downing Street in London? No. No. No.
The big red button sits in the Oval
Office on the desk of the American
president which means the UK's nuclear
deterrent is a deterrent only name. It's
controlled by the US. This is something
I have been saying for years over here
on this show, haven't I? And here you
have official confirmation of this from
the leader of a British political party
that the British nuclear deterrent is
not really a nuclear deterrent. It's
really, it's actually controlled by the
United States, not by the UK. Isn't that
interesting? Right. Should I say I told
you so?
Right. Okay. So, there there is that.
Now, what else is going on? Yeah. Now,
we were talking about NATO, right? That
the Americans are complaining over here
that why are we in NATO? So in 2023, the
US Congress approved a bill barring any
American president from unilaterally
withdrawing from NATO, which means Trump
can't withdraw from NATO even if he
wants to. And guess who guess who
sponsored guess who participated and
voted for the bill?
It was Marco Rubio himself. So Rubio
here is complaining why are we in NATO?
And it was Rubio himself who was
who participated
in passing this bill that prevents any
American president from unilaterally
withdrawing from NATO. Did Mr. Rubio
forget that very conveniently?
So these threats that the Americans are
making, they just bluff.
They are simply bluff, aren't they?
Rubio himself has tweeted this. No US
president should be able to withdraw
from NATO without Senate approval. So
they will need a majority in the Senate
in order to be able to withdraw from
NATO. I think the Republicans currently
have a majority in the Senate, but let's
see how things go. Yeah. So there is
this that's going on. What else do we
have? And this is interesting. This is
uh the Italian Prime Minister Madame
Meloney. Madame Georg Maloney. And she
has made this really
surprising statement. I accuse Israel of
crossing the red line. I condemn the
massacre of Palestinian civilians and I
announce that Italy will support
European sanctions against Israel.
That's an incredible statement,
right? Incredible statement from Madame
Maloney.
So, looks like the Europeans don't want
to participate in this war and the the
sentiment in Europe seems to be turning
against Israel for some reason. Very
interesting. Very interesting.
Okay, what else? Uh there's another
interesting piece of news. UK security
officials have started withholding
intelligence from the US due to Trump's
erratic and and yeah erratic behavior.
The British officials feel the fear that
British secrets will not remain
classified as the American president has
no compulsion about screwing over
America's allies. So there's no trust
now. No one trusts Trump. No one trusts
the US. None of the vasals trusts the
United Nations anymore, right? Chaotic
foreign policy, repeated criticism of
Kir Tmer and so on. A decadesl long
intelligence relationship has been
plunged into uncertainty after
Washington's threats to Greenland, its
ambition to interfere in European
politics and public outrage over
Britain's refusal to join the American
war against Iran.
Right? So there's, you know, there's
this situation where the American vasals
are losing trust in the US and, you
know, they they are they are starting to
withhold information and intelligence
from the Americans.
Uh here here's an interesting piece of
news. After a 7-year hiatus, this is
2026, 7 years means 2019. So after a
7-year hiatus, India is about to import
its first Iranian oil.
Yeah, India is about to import its first
Iranian oil at $100 roughly a barrel.
Quite the achievement in Washington for
the long-term strength of the economic
and financial sanctions regime. Well,
that's an interesting piece of news.
Let's see how that goes. Yeah, let's see
how that goes. Now, that here's one more
piece of news that's not related that's
not connected to the war, but
nevertheless, it's important for India.
France France refuses Rafal source codes
to India triggering major blow to New
Delhi's air power independence strategy.
So the news it's it it was from March
31st. Today is April the 2nd. So Paris
has reportedly denied India access to
the Rafal fighters core source codes
preventing New Delhi from independently
modifying the tales uh ASA radar uh the
mission computer and the electronic
warfare suite.
Um so French authorities
confirmed that New Delhi will not
receive access to the Rafal fighters
core source codes a refusal that
directly impacts India's ability to
independently modify critical electronic
and electronic warfare systems. So if
India pays a tremendous amount of money
to acquire these fighter planes should
India not have the complete
authority and complete power to change
anything in the aircraft once we
purchase them. They should be ours,
right? But no, you purchase them, but
you still can't modify everything. Some
things you will need for French help
every time to to modify. And each time
you need French help, they will ask for
money.
That's what the French want to do. This
is the kind of behavior that you
typically see from the Americans.
And look, it's a French aircraft. The
French have the right to, you know,
impose whatever conditions they want.
But then India should have the right
If India is sensible to not buy these
aircraft, the French seem to think that
since India has bought 36 or whatever
Rafals, that's why it's it's almost a
done deal that India will have to buy
more and that's why they think that they
can now arm twist India and extract more
concessions from India.
Right? So the French authorities say
that the software architecture is highly
sensitive and it's closely guarded
technology developed over many years and
that's why they cannot part with it.
They can't share it with the Indians.
And India is proposing to acquire up to
114 more Rafal fighters under the MRFA
program. And this deal is estimated at
approximately 36 billion American
dollars. Yeah.
One of the largest combat aviation
procurements in modern defense history.
And one one French report stated
unequivocally India will not receive
sensitive source codes for Rafa's radar
and electronic office suite the French
the France the France will retain
control over core software despite
technology transfer and local production
cooperation.
Okay.
So source code control determines
whether India can independently
integrate indigenous weapons such as the
Astra beyond visual range missile or
potentially the Brahmos air launched
cruise missile without recurring
approval cycles from France and other
from Dasalt Aviation and other other
French defense firms.
So um that's the issue and at the same
time the Russians
have proposed to sell the Sukoy 57 fifth
generation fighter plane to India and
provide full source code access to India
including design documentation and
customization authority right
so so that's the question India is in
this situation now India has to make a
decision what does India two does India
give in to French arm twisting or does
India actually go ahead and say no to
France and purchase Sukoy 57s so one
more new aircraft into India's inventory
okay but it's a Sukoy and it's in some
ways
something that integrates with India's
Sukoy 30 fighter planes so it's not
going to be a tremendously different
aircraft
I'm sure some components will be will be
similar and I'm sure you can use the
same production line for that was used
for Sukoy30s to manufacture Suko 57s. Uh
and then there's the question of the
Russians. The Russians themselves
haven't been extremely reliable.
Okay, we've had issues with the Russians
when it comes to the a to the FGFA
fighter plane program which was the
precursor to the Sukoy 57. We've had
issues with the Russians about spare
parts of various arm systems. We've had
issues with the Russians about the
aircraft carrier that they sold to us,
Admiral Gorskov. So what does India do?
That's the question.
India is currently,
you know, the number of squadrons,
fighter plane squadrons that we have,
they they are way below what we should
have, right? The number of squadrons we
should have, I don't know, we have 29 or
30 or 31 squadrons and we should have I
don't know what number 39, 40, whatever
the number is, right?
So that is the dilemma India is in. It's
been years and years we've been talking
about purchasing or buying or
manufacturing or whatever and they are
making no progress whatsoever. So what
should India do is the question. I think
pay attention to what's happening in
Iran. Are fighter planes dominating the
skies? No. Fighter planes are not
dominating the skies. Fighter planes are
being shot down.
F-35 fighter planes, F-15 fighter
planes, all kind of fighter planes have
been shot down by the Iranians. Iranian
fighter planes have been shot down by
the Americans. And what is doing the
shooting down? It's not fighter plane
shooting down fighter plane. It's
missiles shooting down fighter planes.
And what is doing the most destruction
in the war? It's drones and missiles. So
what India should do
is focus on India's AMCA. Don't buy the
Rafal, don't buy the Sukoy, or maybe buy
a bunch of Sukoys, whatever, but focus
on the AMC. Focus on jet engines. And if
the AMC comes into production in a in a
decade from now, okay, in the meanwhile,
India should focus on drones and
missiles, various kinds of missiles.
India should build up a stockpile of
more than a million drones of various
kinds and more than 10, 20, 30,000
missiles of various kinds including
cruise missiles, supersonic, hypersonic,
subsonic cruise missiles, ballistic
missiles.
That's what India should do because the
wars of the future are going to be
fought with drones and missiles, not
with fighter planes. Fighter planes are
obsolete now. They're becoming more and
more obsolete just like aircraft
carriers. So maybe it's a and India
should also focus on unmanned combat
aircraft aerial vehicles like the Gatak.
This is the future of aerial warfare not
fighter planes. I think India's mindset
is still stuck in the 20th century.
Right? So uh that's the thing that's
what uh I think India should do. India
should learn the lessons of the wars
others are fighting. We should not wait
for us having to fight a war and then
learn some lessons. No, learn the
lessons that are that are you know that
are visible that that can be learned
from other people's wars and other
people's mistakes. So that's what India
needs to do. Lots lots and lots and lots
of drones of various kinds including
Indian versions of the shahed or
whatever other drones and missiles of
various kinds including and India should
not think of ballistic missiles as
something that's used to deliver the
nuclear deterrent. No, ballistic
missiles should be used for delivering
conventional munitions also. That's why
India should needs to have tens of
thousands of missiles.
See, I mean, see how many missiles the
Americans and Israelis and the Iranians
have used up in the just one month of
war. Thousands, I suppose. Thousands.
So, if India has to fight a war, a
two-front war, China and Pakistan, we're
going to have to spend we're going to
have to shoot thousands of missiles
every month.
So I think India should have a stockpile
of 100,000 missiles at least and several
million drones. That's what India needs
to do. Quantity has a quality of its
own.
Okay. Anyway, so that is what's going
on. Uh India is facing challenges. India
is facing challenges when it comes to
energy. The straight of foremost is
closed, selectively closed. Some uh uh
some tankers, oil tankers are being
allowed to cross.
uh the Iranians are allowing oil tankers
to cross the street of Armos if they are
going to India.
But there's also the threat that the
straight of Bab al-Bandde could also be
closed by the Houthis because the
Houthis are allied with Iran. And if
Iran faces more punishment by the
Americans and Israelis, they will
activate the Houthis who will close the
state of Babel Bandib. And then the oil
that's coming into India from Russia
will also stop. Then what do we do? The
Ukrainians have destroyed or damaged
significantly at least three or four
Russian ports
which are at the forefront of Russia's
oil exports. So Russia's uh capacity to
export oil has dropped by about 40% and
Russia is just sitting and taking the
punishment.
So super complicated situation right
now. The war in the Gulf region and the
war in Ukraine are now interconnected
and uh and India could face uh India,
China, Russia, not Russia, India, China,
Japan, other nations could could face uh
potentially if the war goes on shortages
of uh of fuel whether it is uh oil which
gives rise to diesel, petrol, kerosin,
jet fuel etc. and also cooking oil sorry
cooking gas and I am aware of several
restaurants in large cities in India
that that have already shut down because
of a shortage of gas right so yeah that
is the situation so the longer this war
goes on the more problematic it's going
to be for the entire world but can the
US end the war the US is it in a
position to end the war will the
Israelis allow the US to end the war and
if the US ends the or in such a way that
it has to withdraw militarily from West
Asia, then Iran becomes the regional
hedgemon.
Even if Iran is damaged, pounded,
devastated, it still has the ability to
destroy all the nations in the region.
And that means that Iran can then impose
its will on the Gulf nations if the
Americans are have to withdraw. And then
what happens? These Gulf nations are oil
producing nations. and Iran will demand
that they sell oil and do transactions
of oil in non-dollar currencies
and that's a disaster for the US. That's
why the US cannot withdraw right now
from the war. So whatever Trump says
he's
he he has dug a hole for himself a deep
hole for himself and I don't see how
he's going to extricate himself out out
of this. is going to get more and more
desperate the next two three weeks if uh
things don't change.
Uh so that's where we are. Okay, that's
my analysis. Okay, now let's take some
questions. What questions do we have? H
Patel says two questions. How difficult
would it be for Iran to develop a
missile with a range of 6,000 plus
miles? Hypothetically, what would happen
if Iran managed to target a major US
city during this war?
Okay. Miles to kilometers. What's 1.5
1.6? What is it? So 6,000 * 60.
So it's about 9,000 10,000 km you're
talking about. How difficult would it be
for Iran to de develop a missile of that
range? So right now the Iranians seem to
have missile have missiles of 2 to 4,000
km range. Now understand this one thing,
okay, about ballistic missiles. A
ballistic missile doesn't have a set
range. a ballistic missile. Let's say it
has a range of a stated range of 2,000
kilometers hypothetically. Okay? And a
payload capacity of let's say uh 1 ton.
Okay? Let's say 1 ton payload capacity,
which means it can have
a warhead or multiple warheads that
cumulatively have a weight of 1 ton
hypothetically. And with that payload,
the missile can travel 2,000 km. But
what if I cut down the payload from
1,000 kg to 100 kg? 90% reduction.
Then the range increases,
right? You may be able to almost
potentially double the range by reducing
the payload.
And all it takes to have an even longer
range is more propellant, more fuel.
And if you are if you have good
engineers, it's not that hard to do
that. Of course, you've got to test the
missiles. Right. And the Iranians have
been testing it. They've done a lot of
tests in the past month.
So I don't think it is very difficult
for Iran to to develop missiles with
much longer ranges. They currently have
missiles that can target Diego Garcia,
which is about 4,000 km away from the
Iranian coastline, which means that Iran
can, if they want, they can target any
city within Western Europe.
Okay.
Now, if you want to cross the Atlantic,
hypothetically, that's what another
3,000 4,000 km. So, that's about 8,000.
Yeah. So, u I don't think it is very
difficult for Iran to do this. Now, what
would happen if Iran managed to target a
major US city during this war? Well,
Iran isn't crazy enough to do that. Iran
is a very rational nation as we have
seen from their behavior during this
war. So, this war has gone on for a
month and Iran has taken no rash steps.
They have made no rash rash actions,
crazy actions.
Whatever they have been doing, they have
been doing in retaliation and in
response to escalations
and provocations by the US and by
Israel. Understand who started this war?
This is just a hard fact, okay? It's not
my opinion. Who started the war? It is
Israel and the US that started the war.
Israel did not hit, you know, hit first.
Isra, sorry, Iran did not hit first.
Iran did not
do the first strike. It was Israel and
the US that did the first strikes and
then Iran responded.
And then when the Americans destroyed a
desalination plant in Kashm Island, the
Iranians responded with desalination of
somewhere destruction of a desalination
plant near Fujira. When the Americans
and Israelis struck oil oil reservoirs,
oil dep depots, the Iranians did the
same thing. So they are doing tit for
tat but they are not going crazy. When
the Americans uh destroyed an Iranian
school with 170 little children in it,
the Iranians did not do something like
that. Right?
Uh the Americans have hit Iranian
nuclear facilities. Iran thus far has
not targeted Dimona in Israel. They have
threatened Dimona but not targeted it
directly. So Iran has been very very
very you could say
responsible if that word can be used in
this war and I don't think they will do
something as stupid as targeting a major
US city but if they do it then then then
I suppose if they target a major US city
hypothetically which they will never do
but they if they do it I think then
Trump may unleash
more punitive actions such as the
forbidden weapons possibly. Today
Ritik Paw says in this war who is
winning and who is losing so far? I did
a long analysis. I hope that gave you
the answer that nobody is winning.
Nobody is losing right now. Um you could
say Iran is taking a tremendous amount
of damage.
But so you can say that the Americans
and Israelis are they are tactically
doing great but strategically it's Iran
that's winning. See what is victory for
Iran? the survival of the nation and the
survival of the regime of the ayatas. If
that happens, Iran has won
the Americans and Israel is the
Caribbean with an objective of
destroying Iran and doing a regime
change. That's what they've said on the
first day of the war. Now that the tunes
have changed
now that now the story is that the
Americans want complete destruction of
Iran's uh nuclear program, complete
destruction of Iran's drone
capabilities, missile capabilities, and
the opening of the state of Hormuz. If
the Americans can't achieve these
things, well, they haven't won. They
have actually failed in achieving their
objectives. So, I think Iran currently,
you know, against all odds,
you could say it's it's
succeeding thus far. Yeah.
Iran, you see, we in India talk about
fighting a two-front war, two and a half
front war. That's what we're worried
about. Iran is fighting a seven, eight,
nine front war at the same time. It's
fighting all these nations at the same
time and it's still on top. Yeah. Uh
they are taking obviously tremendous
damage. The amount of damage they've
taken will cost them maybe hundreds of
billions of dollars, maybe trillions of
dollars to undo repair. Okay, it will
take decades to do that. And yet
it's Iran that is actually, you know,
succeeding in what it wants to do.
It's the Americans in Israel is who are
not able to achieve what they want.
Mandar Kirkar says uh does the deep
state think it's time for World War II?
Well, it depends.
So, like I said, World War II means a
lot more nations getting involved in
this matter, right? In this war. Trump
is trying to drag the Europeans into the
war at some point in time. He he may
even activate Pakistan.
So it looks like Trump wants more
nations to join the war. If the European
nations join the war, it means that
Russia and China may also potentially
consider very strongly joining the war.
Right? It may lead to severe escalations
not just in Persian in the Persian Gulf
region, also in Ukraine potentially
because all the options that the
Americans and Israelis have on the
table, Putin also has those options on
on the table visi Ukraine.
So if the Americans escalate, if Trump
drags more nations into the war, then
there could be massive escalations and
that is what you could call World War
II. I hope it doesn't happen, but we are
close to it. We're not very far far away
from it.
Arun has become a new member. Thank you
very much, Arun and welcome to the
channel's membership. Thank you.
Chirang Shirinat says, "A slightly
off-topic question. What extent did the
Afghan war along with the Pistoica
Glasnos and the US-led arms race
following the Star Wars program
contribute to the collapse of the USSR?
There's a lot of factors that caused the
collapse of the USSR. There's no one
factor that you can point out, but uh
the Afghan war was definitely u a very
major setback for the USSR.
They also seem to have thought that, you
know, they'll just walk into Afghanistan
and just take over the nation.
And they fought there for close to a, I
don't know, close to a decade. Yeah. And
eventually they had to retreat without
achieving any any of their objectives.
Uh, and that was a huge huge blow to the
morale of the nation, to the prestige of
the nation.
And it definitely contributed uh to it
was one of the contributing factors to
the uh collapse of the USSR. Uh because
see
for such a gigantic nation to remain
unified the central government the polit
bureau it needs to show that it is it is
successful in what it does and if it is
humiliated by a small rag rag tag nation
like Afghanistan according to them rag
according to them then the other states
that are part of the USSR
they will be emboldened to seek more
autonomy and seek independence because
it's clear that the that the nation
doesn't have a high quality military and
so on. So that was one contributing
factor. Peristoric Glasnos was another
big contributing factor because it
um it for the first time allowed
criticism of the government. Okay.
Officially paristoic and was was about
openness. It was about self-criticism.
It was about admitting responsibility
for shortcomings and so on. So that's
that's when for the first time you know
you you had open criticism of the
government people pointing fingers and
and pointing out the the the the
shortfall shortcomings and mistakes of
the government and overall that caused
you know a decline in the morale of the
nation a decline in in in people's
confidence in in their leadership in
their nation and that that per permeates
down all the way to every level of
society including the bureaucracy
including the administrative uh sector
including the military and when you have
this overall
uh you know uh low confidence situation
in a nation it it makes it way more easy
for the nation to you know fracture if
it's such a large nation a US-led arms
race all these things all these things
they contributed in a variety of ways
Chernobyl in a small way contributed but
overall it was the decline in the
standards in the USSR from 1960s all all
the way to the 19 late 1980s and 1990s
that caused the decline and eventual
dissolution of the USSR.
Vickskagula, thank you very much. Vikola
Vikola says, "There's an intense
misinformation campaign carried out in
this war. What's your opinion on the
impact on countries like UAE? Damage
assessment, please." Uh, misinformation
campaign.
All media has some element of
misinformation.
All media, all news is propaganda.
Please understand that. If you imagine
that any news channel is 100% unbiased
and balanced and neutral, if you imagine
that, then you are living in La La Land.
Everyone has some bias. I am biased, by
the way. I am the first to say this. I
am not a neutral person. I am biased. I
am not biased towards the US. I'm not
biased towards Israel. I'm not biased
towards China. I'm not biased towards
Russia. I'm not biased towards Iran. I
am biased towards India
and everything I say to you,
you know, you have to understand that I
I carry some bias in me. I am biased
towards my nation and my civilization.
Everybody is biased. But at least I
admit it openly, right?
Most of your analysts and journalists
and experts, they will pretend to be
neutral.
They all are biased in some way or the
other. Some of them may have unknowing
unknown biases that they are not aware
of within themselves and some of them
may actually be hypothetically
paid to push certain kinds of agendas
and propaganda.
And when it comes to foreign media, I'm
talking about Indian media also. Okay?
But when it comes to foreign media
whether it's BBC whether it's CNN
whether it is uh u CCTN whether it is
develutnik
everything is propaganda everyone is
pushing their own agenda Yeah, if you
don't understand this, then you're going
to be very badly misled. If you imagine
that the the news that you're reading or
watching, it's the truth. No, it's not.
And the Indian media is a very low
quality media overall. Not all, some of
these, some of them are good, of course,
but overall, most of them are super
mediocre. Most of them don't even
understand what what journalistic best
practices are.
Okay? If the BBC and CNN said something,
it doesn't mean it's the truth. Some of
them don't understand that.
I very surprising and very shocking for
me to to realize this. Some of them
don't understand that if the B BBC
reports something or the CNN reports
something, it doesn't mean it's the
truth. And you don't start repeating it
in the Indian media. But most Indian
media outlets simply regurgitate, simply
repeat
the talking points of the western media.
That way, there's no need to do research
of your own. just watch the news on BBC
then come and speak in Hindi or whatever
language the same things and then you
look so informed and so such an such an
expert.
So uh that is the deal. So there is
definitely a massive very intense
misinformation propaganda campaign being
carried out on this war not just in uh
mainstream media also on social media.
Social media platforms are biased.
Social media platforms have algorithms
that suppress certain kinds of news.
There are various nations that have impo
that have imposed tremendous censorship
of news, news blackouts in some
countries right now. If if you are
living there, you are not allowed to
take a video of what's happening.
So there's a tremendous amount of
misinformation out there. It's very hard
to know what's actually happening. The
first two three days of the war, it was
very clear what was happening based on
the reports on Twitter and then suddenly
all the reports disappeared,
you know.
Uh so yeah uh what's my opinion on the
impact on nations like the UAE?
Well for the UAE it's a difficult time.
Okay let's take the UAE as an example.
The UAE is this small nation, very
friendly towards India. Very good
nation.
About 60% of the population of the UAE
is from the subcontinent. About 40% of
the population of the UEE is of Indian
origin. They are not citizens
but they live there. So the UAE has well
the two major cities or the two major
emirates in the UAE are Dubai and Abu
Dhabi. Abu Dhabi's economic model is
mainly oil. They have the Abu Dhabi
National Oil Corporation Adno which is a
major oil exporter.
And then Dubai has a totally different
economic model. Dubai doesn't have much
oil. So Dubai has positioned itself as a
resort city. It's a gigantic resort,
okay, for high netw worth individuals,
rich people, wealthy people. You can you
so they will they well if you are a
wealthy person and you can afford to
live in the city, they welcome you with
open arms. So all the residents of the
of of of Dubai are wealthy people.
But the majority of the population of
the of of Dubai is actually uh the
workers. So in a resort you may have 15
guests but you may have 200 employees
who service the guests who give whatever
services that the guests require. So for
10 or 15 guests you need 200 employees.
So that sort of thing you have in Dubai
it's it's a massive resort. Now, when
there's a war
and the American promise of military
protection turns out to be um an
illusion and you have drones flying in
and hitting hotels that that that are
hosting American armed forces personnel
and you have some casualties, then the
high netw worth individuals, they will
all flee the city, right? So, a lot of
people have left uh Dubai apparently,
especially ultra rich people.
There's a lot of people who have not
left Dubai also who are still staying
on. Okay. But the longer the war lasts
and the longer there is this you know
air of uncertainty and potential
military activity uh the longer this
this lasts the more unviable this
economic model will become. So for Abu
Dhabi it will be fine because they can
keep on selling oil. For Dubai it's
going to be a disaster if it this if
this goes on for 6 months 1 year or
whatever. Right? Uh but overall Iran has
not indiscriminately bombed Abu Dhabi or
Dubai. They've only hit military targets
and hotels where allegedly American
military personnel are staying. Okay.
Hanei says, "What happens if the Gulf
nations stop supporting the US war? Can
it backstab the US by giving US army
targets and locations to Iran to end the
war? Is it possible? Iran doesn't need
any information from the Gulf nations.
Why does Iran need information from the
Gulf nations? You can just take you can
open Google maps and see the locations
of the American bases in the Gulf
region. You don't need information from
the from the Gulf nations, right? The
American military bases are very visible
from satellites, from even free
satellite imagery like Google Maps or
Google Earth. And the Iranians have
access to high quality Chinese military
satellite imagery in almost real time.
So Iran knows exactly what's happening
and what is where. They know exactly
where the radars are. They've taken out
a number of very very expensive and
valuable radars. They know exactly where
the American refueling aircraft are.
They know exactly where the American
Awax aerial radar aircraft were
stationed. And they've done pinpoint
strikes on these things.
So why does Iran need any information
about targets and locations from the
Gulf nations? And the Gulf nations won't
do it. They are not stupid. They are not
suicidal, right? They won't do it. They
have some sense.
Okay. So, uh that that's not going to
happen. Now, what happens if the Gulf
nations stop supporting the US war? How
can they stop supporting the US war?
They have already given the Americans
bases in their territory. They can't ask
the Americans to leave, but they don't
have to ask the Americans to leave
because the Iranians have already
destroyed the bases
or rendered them mostly inoperable.
So essentially one month into the
conflict,
uh it's almost a certainty
that most if not all of the American
military bases in the region have been
destroyed.
The fifth fleet headquarters
in Bahrain,
one of the biggest naval installations
in the region, has been devastated by
Iranian missiles and drones,
right? And and so the same applies to
other American military installations in
the region. So I don't think uh the Gulf
nations need to stop the port in the US.
The US is being pushed out of the region
by Iranian strikes.
Ranu Nahapana says who was Mahakshhatra
Ishwar Singh related to Sakas? I am not
aware of who this was. Ishwar Sen
Mahakhatra Ishwar Sen.
I don't think I've come across this
name.
When it comes to Mahakhatraas, I know
about Nahapana. I know of Chashtana. I
know of Rdra Dhaman and other
Mahakhatraas. I am not aware of Ishwar
Sin. Sorry.
Warrior says, "Is India preparing for a
military operation? There have been
serious CCS meetings and siren testings.
All three military leaders are visiting
temples.
Look, I am a civilian.
I
am not involved in any shape or form in
the Indian government, in the Indian
military or in the Indian intelligence
services.
So I am not aware of whether India is
preparing for any kind of military
operation. I would say that currently
the situation is tense. There is a war
that's going on in our backyard
unfortunately
and that war could escalate.
Yeah, we know that Pakistan is a rogue
nation. It's a terrorist nation.
Pakistan and Afghanistan have an ongoing
conflict going on. Right? So we have to
be very alert right now.
Pakistan is a treacherous nation. We
have to be very alert and that's why I'm
sure the government of India is
conducting routine precautionary
precautionary measures and so on. Maybe
they're testing out sirens just to make
sure that everything is operational in
case something is needed. Military
leaders visiting temples. Well, I I
don't know anything about that.
It's good that military doesn't visit
temples. I have nothing against that. Of
course, I I welcome that. But I don't
know if it is an indicator of something
that's going to happen. So I answer is I
am not aware of what's going on.
Omupali says analyze that if Iran wins,
petrol dollar ends, US economic might
might ends less money to spend on
military hard power in total decrease in
Taiwan, South Korea falls, China, North
Korea are waiting for the right moment.
Okay.
Let's say hypothetically Iran wins. So
what is the definition of an Iranian
victory? The definition of an Iranian
victory is that Iran Iran's government
continues to exist.
Iran's nuclear facilities are not
destroyed. Nuclear capabilities are not
destroyed. Iran's drone stockpile is not
destroyed. India's uh sorry, Iran's uh
missile stockpile is not destroyed. they
continue to have the ability to to use
drones and missiles whenever they want.
Okay, that's number one. Number two, the
state of Horus remains closed. Uh and
number three, the Americans, they lose
all their military bases in the region
because Iran has destroyed them. So then
how does the how does the US return to
the region with military force when they
have no military bases that that that
survive?
If you want to station
fighter planes, drones, uh, radars,
military personnel somewhere, you need
military bases. You can't put them in a
city, right? And if the Iranians have
destroyed your military bases, it means
the Americans can't
set up operations there, which means
that they lose their ability to project
power in the region, in the Gulf region.
That is the definition of an Iranian
victory. State of also remains closed.
So if this happens and the Americans
withdraw or are forced to withdraw from
the Gulf region
and then what happens is that even if
Iran is very badly devastated, it is
still the most powerful
nation in the region because it still
has maybe one lakh drones and maybe
several thousand missiles. So nobody
dares
nobody dares to speak against Iran or do
anything against Iran.
In that situation, what Iran can do is
it can demand
that every Gulf nation whenever it does
oil transactions, it does those oil
transactions in a non US dollar
currency,
maybe Chinese yuan.
If that happens, the petro dollar system
starts collapsing.
Okay? If the petro dollar system starts
collapsing, the US dollar loses value
rapidly.
I don't know rapidly or not, maybe over
a course of 2, three years.
If that happens, the US obviously has
less money to spend
on everything including power projection
capabilities, military hard power,
salaries, blah blah blah, all that
stuff.
Then what does the US do?
And in the meanwhile, China learns all
the lessons of this war. It bulks up its
massive stockpiles of missiles and
drones. China has an enormous mil
military industrial complex. They can
churn out missiles and drones and
submarines and ships like sausages.
So maybe let's say China stockpiles
millions of drones and tens of thousands
of missiles. And then Xiinping says,
"Okay, move on Taiwan." What happens?
What can the US do? Nothing much. China
wins. Taiwan may be destroyed perhaps.
Okay, but China still gets, you know, uh
gets possession of the island, let's
say. And if China makes a move on
Taiwan, the Americans will force Japan
and South Korea to get into a war with
China, which means now we have a major
war in that region.
Right? So the question is, is China
willing
to take that risk of going to war with
Taiwan, South Korea, and Japan and the
US at the same time?
that starts sounding like World War II
once again, right? Uh so yeah, these are
all very dangerous situations if they
happen.
But just by winning this war, Iran can
start the process of collapsing the
petro dollar system and start the
downward fall of the US dollar in terms
of value.
Aman Sharma says, "I am a software
engineer and I want to create a software
that can go global and useful to the
country. In which area should I
research? Thanks for guiding." I don't
know. I don't know. You have to uh
analyze the business landscape very very
uh carefully.
See if you want to create a software.
So okay you're a software engineer you
have the skills you need to choose you
know forget about the platform and
forget about all that forget about the
technology that they use to create the
software
you to ask yourself what do you want to
create a web app do you want to create a
mobile app do you want to create a SAS
SAS I don't know how viable SAS is in
today's AI agentic environment okay and
you want a software that is popular that
goes global it's useful for the country
so you Decide what niche you want to be
in. Okay? If it goes global, it means it
it will be very popular. So decide what
it is. What what does it take for a
software or or a product to to become
popular globally? And if it's something
that will become popular globally, how
can it help the country? So this
analysis you have to do. I have never
not done this analysis. So I can't just
sit here and tell you out of my
imagination what will work, what will
not work. I have no idea. You have to
spend time. You have to spend hours
analyzing what works, what doesn't work.
What do people want? What do people
like? What do people love? What do
people crave?
Then the things that people crave. Can
they actually be helpful for the
country? You know, think about these
things. This is something you have to
do, sir. Okay. This takes a lot of time
and effort.
And what you can do
is
you can spend months doing this analysis
and then then create one software which
may or may not work. Or what you can do
is you can start trying lots of ideas.
Ship one
um one product every week for the next
one year. So in one year you have 52
products that have gone that have gone
out and see how is the demand how is the
response out of those 52 products maybe
maybe 5% will become popular maybe 3%
will become popular
right
so even if 10% out of 50 that's five so
even after one year if two of your
products become popular you'll make good
money and you will understand what works
what doesn't work right so I think the
better approach is to ship one product a
week for one year and see how it goes.
That way you have a much higher chance
of success compared to spending 6 months
doing your research and then shipping
one product after that. So I think
that's what you should do. Try lots of
different ideas. If you are a software
engineer, you already have the tools and
the skills. Okay? Start pushing out lots
of products. Push one product out into
production every week for the next one
year. And then I'm sure you will get a
way better understanding and feel for
what works, what doesn't work, what is
popular, what what has the potential to
be popular, what uh is not going to work
and what can be helpful for the country.
That's what I would suggest you should
do. All right. All the best sir.
Du Patel says you mentioned census
yesterday government announced. Well,
I'm so glad. I'm so glad. Finally.
Finally a step in the right direction. I
am very glad. Good. I'm glad Ritik
Hilwani says Russia takes a second
strike by Ukraine on oil refinery. They
have taken multiple strikes. Not second
strike, multiple strikes. And
from sitting over here far away from
Russia. Okay, I am not there so I don't
know what's actually happening on the
ground, but it looks like the Russians
are just sitting and taking it. Bang,
bang, bang. Okay, all right. Let's do
let's take more. I don't know what
Russia is doing. Why isn't Russia
taking some steps to prevent Ukraine
from launching more strikes?
Not sure what Russia is doing. I'm not
sure what the strategy and the
objectives are right now, but Russia is
kind of looking weak right now. Right.
Uh so Russia has taken multiple strikes
on at least three ports from which oil
is exported and in those ports you have
big storage facilities for oil and those
are being hit by Ukrainian drones. So
what the Ukrainians are doing is they
are sending swarms of drones maybe a
thousand drones at the same time flying
low flying over the territories of other
nations until they reach Russia.
Which nations are these? Is it is it
Poland? It's definitely the Baltic
states, Latia, Lithuania, Estonia,
perhaps Poland also. And then it's
striking in the St. Petersburg etc
region. And Russia is just sitting and
taking it. So yeah, Russia looks a
little lost, little weak right now. It's
not a good look for Russia and uh that's
going to have an impact on us also
because that oil it comes here. Yeah. It
comes to India.
Amish. Good evening, ma'am. From mega to
mega destruction, Trump's mask fell off.
So, it was MAGA.
What is mega? Mega.
What's MGA?
Make Israel great again. Is that what
you
um Yeah. So, Trump's uh Trump's uh what
do you say? His his his slogan is MAGA,
right? Make America great again. And
then people have accused him of actually
having the agenda of MIGA which is
making Israel great again. And Trump uh
you know he used to boast that he during
his first term as president he did not
start a single war. The first president
after decades who did that did not start
a single war and during this term
initially he was hankering after a Nobel
prize. He even stole the Nobel Prize of
that lady that that that the Venezuelan
lady whatever her name is
who wanted to become Venezuela's leader
but she was yeah she didn't get what she
want so he even took her medal for
himself because she came and gave it to
him so he wanted no Nobel peace prize
and look at what he's done now in
January he did a regime change in
Venezuela he kidnapped the president of
the nation I mean incredible and now he
has gone and he's in the process of
destroying
the future of Iran, right? It's going to
take Iran decades to rebuild itself
whenever this war eventually stops after
that. And who's going to pay for it? The
Americans won't pay for it. Yeah. So,
Trump's mask is indeed fallen off. Yeah.
his carefully cultivated mask of being a
pacifist and a president who doesn't
start start wars. All of that has fallen
off very rapidly during his second term
as the US president.
Dir Kamat says if the US withdrew from
West Asia, would Iran become the
regional hedgeim or would greater Israel
become the region regional hedgeim? That
seems to be the ploy to be. That's a
good question. That's a good question.
So let's say the US is forced say the US
will not willingly withdraw from West
Asia.
They will want to remain in West Asia.
But if Iran destroys all their military
bases as most as what's most likely
happened and if Iran
continues to have the ability to launch
drones and missiles on demand in
whatever quantity they want, then the
Americans can't stay in the region. They
can't stay in the region. They will have
to withdraw from the region. Their ships
can't be in the region because their
ships will be obliterated by the
Iranians. Drone swarms are you just you
can't defeat drone drone swarms, right?
And if you combine drone sworn attack,
drone swarm attacks with ballistic
missiles, that's that's a devastating
combination. So even aircraft carriers
can't defend against that.
So if Iran forces the United States to
withdraw from West Asia, then who
becomes the regional hedgemon?
Well, Iran definitely will be the
regional hedgemon. Okay. But will Isra
also be a regional hedgeim? That depends
on uh how things go in the in the coming
days and weeks. Um
because Israel seems to actually have
this aspiration of creating a greater
Israel from the Nile all the way to the
Tiger Euphrates region, Mesopotamia
region because I've seen soldiers,
Israeli soldiers, IDF soldiers with that
greater Israel patch on their shoulder.
So it looks like it's an actual agenda
for Israel.
So can Israel actually make this happen?
Right now they are in the process of
occupying
territory that belongs to the nation of
Lebanon.
Okay, that that's what Israel is doing
right now. So, they are expanding their
territorial holdings right now. They've
also taken a little bit of little bit of
territory from Syria. Um when the Assad
regime fell and the terrorist uh al-
Shara or whatever he is, he he took
over.
Um
so if Israel is able to significantly
expand its territory then it could be
more of a hedgeim than it is right now.
Right now Israel it scares other
nations. Other nations are worried about
Israel because it has you know
essentially unlimited support from the
United States in terms of funding in
terms of weapons or whatever right
and also because Israel has nuclear
weapons. But let's say Iran forces the
US to withdraw and then Iran acquires
nuclear weapons then I think Iran
becomes more of a hedge than Israel.
Yeah. So yeah, Israel would definitely
want to become the only hedgemon and
that's why they don't want this war to
end until
the regime in Iran is defeated and
there's a regime change. So, Israel most
likely wants the complete destruction of
Iran and a regime change
and it doesn't look like it's going to
happen soon anytime soon the way things
are going. So, if the war ends the way
it's going right now, I think Iran
becomes the regional ham especially if
it's able to acquire nuclear weapons
quickly.
Sergeant Skylanc says are Pakistani
nukes sovereign. So the fiction that we
are told is that Pakistan developed its
own nuclear weapons through the efforts
through the untiring unseasing efforts
of the Pakistani nuclear scientist Abdul
Kadra Khan Dr. Auk Khan and it is said
that Dr. Aku Khan stole blueprints of
reactors or centrifuges or whatever from
the Netherlands and he came to Pakistan
with those stolen items and that's how
they were able to uh develop a Pakistani
nuclear weapons program and test their
own nukes. That's the fiction we are
told
but I don't buy it at all. Now I don't
have any evidence whatsoever
that the Pak that the nukes on Pakistani
territory are American nukes but I am
99.9% certain that the Pakistani
engineers and scientists don't have the
wherewithal to develop nuclear weapons
on their own. So most likely these
nuclear weapons are American nuclear
weapons. Some people say they are
Chinese nuclear weapons. When Pakistan
was a US vasal in the 1980s and 1990s,
how how do you imagine that the US would
have allowed China
to give nukes to Pakistan which is an
American vasal? I don't see that
happening logically. So most likely the
nuclear weapons on Pakistani territory
are not Pakistani in nature. They are
American nuclear weapons on
on loan to Pakistan and not really on
loan either.
Most likely those nuclear weapons in
Pakistani territory are handled by
Americans only. Pakistanis are not even
able allowed to come near them. That's
most likely what the situation is. So my
answer is that I am strongly strongly of
the opinion without any evidence. Okay.
But I strongly believe that the
Pakistani nukes are not sovereign at
all. they actually belong to the US and
the objective of putting those nukes in
Pakistan is to counterbalance India.
Okay.
Rahul Rahul Ladu says great point. The
lesson here is speed of production
matter more matters more than just
quantity and quality. Big fan of you.
Thank you so much sir. Yeah. Yes. I I
suppose you're talking about uh the
missiles and drones, right? We need to
ramp up our production of missiles and
drones. It's not enough to be able to
maybe manufacture 200 in a year or
something. We need to be able to
manufacture 2,000 in a month or at least
200 in a month. Right? When it comes to
missiles of one kind, maybe we should be
able to manufacture 200 brahos in a
month. But we should also in in parallel
be able to manufacture 200 nearby in a
month and 200 uh you know agni various
various kinds of agnes and we should be
able to manufacture several thousand
drones in a month. That's the kind of
production output we need. That's the
kind of scale we need. So yes, the speed
of production matters and the quality of
course we need decent quality. It
doesn't have to be the best in the
world, but as long as as we have the
quantity and decent quality, then we're
good along with high speed of
production.
Suman Vikant says, "How did Alexander
conquer Persia on the ground?"
Uh, how did this happen?
See, it's a good question. See, like I
say, Persia, it's a very difficult
nation to conquer, right?
As Saddam Hussein discovered in 1980,
it's got all these mountains and
mountain ranges. It's like a fortress.
And if you try to fight in the
mountains, you're going to be defeated
by the locals. So, how did Alexander
managed to conquer Persia?
It's because
there were two pitched battles between
Alexander's army and the army of Daros
III. Dasi.
If Das had dispersed his army across
Iran, refused to give Alexander a fullon
battle at any point in time and just
harassed him continuously every step of
his way through guerrilla warfare and
tactics, Alexander would not have
survived.
But Dios was of the opinion that I am
the emperor of the Persian Empire. I
have this gigantic army. What is this
Alexander in front of me? I'll take my
entire army. I'll face Alexander in
battle in a pitched battle. And that was
the mistake he made. So the the
Macedonian tactics and strategies were
better than the Persian tactics and
strategies. And that's why um
uh that's why
uh Alexander was able to defeat uh Dos
the third two times. What was the first
battle? I forget the name, but the
second was Gaga, which was the decisive
battle. And Dios was defeated twice in
pitched battles. And that's how
Alexander was able to conquer Persia.
If Dios had divided his armed forces all
and and put them all across Persia and
especially used the mountainous ranges
and all the terrain, Alexander did not
stand a chance. See, so Das made a
mistake. Big mistake. Fatal mistake of
course.
Utkash Marati says what is the reason
behind Delhi prepared preparedness
drills? Last time drills happened we
know what followed four airports closed
sirens installed in Jodpur etc.
Well I don't know
um yeah we know what happened last time
such drills happened we had operation
Sindur that happened.
So I I think we should all be kind of
mentally prepared in case something
happens. But I am not aware of whether
there are any plans for something
happening. Maybe the government may have
noticed some kind of activity on the
Pakistani side and that's why we are
just preparing for any eventuality.
That's also a possibility. Another
possibility is maybe we are preparing
for our own action potentially. I don't
know. I'm just guessing. I'm just
speculating here. I have no information.
So my point is I don't know what's
happening. Uh but I'm glad that we are
in a high state of preparedness because
we have a terrorist rogue nation, an
artificial temporary terrorist rogue
nation on our doorstep and we have to be
always prepared for any eventuality.
Pain pain has become a new member. Thank
you very much PNG and welcome to the
channel's membership. Thank you. 24.
Barat says when Great Britain created
Congress, they instilled their Fabian
socialist ideology into it to prevent
India from ever industrializing in the
way the USSR and China did.
See the Congress party was a Gambian
party actually their entire ideology and
their entire
method of functioning was Gandhian in
nature.
The Congress party was was founded it
was created
uh in the 19th century by a British
individual called Alan Octavian Hume
who was a British East India Company or
whatever British official who served in
India for a long time and he is the
infamous person who created the great
hedge of India that caused the deaths of
I don't know lacks maybe millions of
Indians.
Okay, look into it. Would you like to
look into it? Let's see. Okay. The great
hedge of India. So first of all, let's
see Alan Hume.
Alan Octavian Hume.
So this Okay. Alan Octavian Hume. This
this person. Okay. British reformer. Ah
what a great thing to be a reformer
ornithologist civil servant botonist
and was the founder of the Indian
National Congress. But what about the
great hedge of India? Where is that?
Have they removed it?
Have they removed all references to
that?
Ah, Indian customs line. Okay.
So,
uh, Commissioner of Customs.
So, he created the inland customs line.
this this division between two parts of
India. Okay. To prevent the smuggling of
salt from coastal regions into other
parts of India to avoid the substantial
salt tax because the British taxed salt
in India. Okay. And that caused
see it it caused the deaths of of a lot
of people in India. It's impossible to
know how many died of salt deprivation
in India. Um
it. So we don't know how many people
died but a lot of Indians died because
of this okay this this action that Alan
Octaven Hume took but he is portrayed
here as a great reformer who was out
here to reform our society and he was a
founder of the Indian National Congress.
So when did he find found the Indian
National Congress when did the
foundation happen? sometime in the 19th
century.
Where is it? Where is it?
Okay, whatever year it is, I'm not going
to waste my time and dig through this
Wikipedia article. As always, please
remember Wikipedia is not necessarily a
a source of reliable information
especially about Indian history. But
okay, so this guy Alan Hume founded the
Indian National Congress. And if you
will see, if you will examine the kind
of leaders the Indian National Congress
had, you will find that you know
millions of Indians, lacks and crows of
Indians became members of the Congress
party uh during the pre947 period. Okay.
But the leaders of the Congress party,
if you see who they were, they were
almost exclusively
English-speaking in British educated
people
and all more or less um you know
predisposed towards a nonviolent
resistance of the British occupation of
India, not violent resistance,
right? Uh and then you had uh the great
Mr. Nehu and the great Mr. Gandhi. You
also had the great Mr. Patel and then
you had Mr. Bose Subhashundra Bose who
became the president of the INC but who
was then outmaneuvered by Mr. Gandhi.
Mr. Gandhi engineered a coup within the
Indian National Congress that ousted Mr.
Bose from the presidency or leadership
of the Indian National Congress. So Mr.
Gandhi knew that Mr. Bose was not a
pacifist. He was he did not believe in
nonviolence. He believed in
getting rid of the British by hook or by
crook. And that's why Mr. Gandhi was
against Mr. Bose and he outmaneuvered
him and engineered a political coup
against Mr. Bose.
And eventually when you had India's
so-called independence in 1947 which was
actually dominion status uh then the uh
then there was a vote an internal vote
within the congress party okay about who
will become the first prime minister of
India and you would have different
congress congress uh you know divisions
shakas or whatever it was within India
who would their leaders would come and
you know vote for who will become the
first prime minister of India.
And the majority of the votes went for
Mr. Patel. So Sardar Patel and no one
voted in favor of Mr. Nero. So Mr.
Gandhi took Mr. Patel for a walk and he
said Patel, Mr. Patel, you need to
withdraw your candidature and support
Mr. Neu. And so Mr. Patel agreed to what
Mr. Gandhi said. He obeyed the order. He
withdrew from the candidature. And
despite Mr. Neu not getting any votes,
he became he was appointed by Mr. Gandhi
as the first prime minister of India and
it was Mr. Neu who was a Fabian
socialist.
I don't think there were too many other
Congress leaders who were Fabian
socialists. It was Mr. Nu who was that
and Fabian socialism was all about very
slow very gradual
economic growth. It wasn't about massive
progress and massive rapid natural
growth.
Fabian socialism was about slow gently
gently gently gently growth and that's
what Mr. Nehu was all about. So Mr.
Gandhi ensured that a Fabian socialist
becomes the prime minister of India and
that ensured that India suffered from
the Nehuian rate of growth for decades
and those precious decades were lost
when India could have grown very rapidly
and that's the deal.
Kunal Vashish says assume that Trump is
a genius and is playing a long-term
game. Please analyze the ad with the the
the advant advantage America will have
with economic collapse, resources,
currency, food etc.
Assume Trump is a genius. Okay, let us
uh play a game of suspension of
disbelief. You see when you watch
certain movies sometimes you have to
suspend your disbelief and say okay this
doesn't make sense but okay let's play
along and just so that we are
entertained let's let's assume that's
correct. some stupid things they will
show which don't make any sense in real
life but okay let's let's just watch it
let's suspend our disbelief and let's
watch the movie so that we are
entertained so you are asking me to
suspend my disbelief and assume that
Trump is a genius and it's playing some
kind of long-term game so what
advantages will the US have with
economic collapse resources currency
food etc look
if Trump is a genius the US wins this
war if the US wins this war, everything
will be hunky and dory.
Okay. The straight of hormones will open
again. The world will have oil on
America's terms from Iran.
Uh the US dollar will stay strong.
Resources will be available every to to
whoever wants on American terms. So if
Trump is a genius, then America wins
this war and everything is fine for the
US. And if Trump is not a genius, then
the US loses this war and then
everything goes wrong for the US. Okay.
So if Iran wins this war and the
straight of Horbus remains closed or it
remains open only on Iran's terms and if
the Houthis can block the Babal Bandibit
then nations like India, Japan etc will
have to purchase oil from the US. So
that is advantageous for the US. But if
the US is forced to withdraw from West
Asia because Iran has won the war, then
Iran
and all the Gulf nations will sell oil
in nond dollar currencies, probably
Chinese yuan. That weakens the US dollar
gradually over time and significantly.
And that's very bad for the US. It's a
disaster for the US, right? Their
economy will will be in very bad shape.
There'll be inflation. There will be
prices going out of control. there'll be
shortages.
So if Trump is a genius and he wins the
Iran war, then everything is fine long
term. But if Trump is a genius and loses
the Iran war, then things don't look
good for the US. Okay.
Hershit Par says, can we expect RA with
Iran instead of India? The RIC with Iran
is already there kind of right because
see Russia and Iran have strategic
military cooperation. Iran has been
supplying very large quantities of
Shahed drones to Russia which Russia has
been employing in the Ukraine war. China
and Iran also have a long-term strategic
partnership. Okay, they have signed a
strategic agreement a 25ear strategic
agreement.
So you already have that sort of RA
Russia, Iran, China.
But uh the more
powerful RA that could emerge would be
Russia, India, China. But uh um I'm not
sure how viable that is. It will all
depend on the outcome of the Iran war.
If Iran wins this war, if the US is
forced to withdraw from West Asia, India
will have way more leverage over the US
in a variety of things and India, you
know, may behave very different from the
way it's behaving right now. So it will
all depend on what happens, what's the
outcome of this current war.
Jimmy Lee says, "Please check the latest
shard of Turin finding." I I saw some I
saw the news reports.
So scientists have analyzed the DNA from
the sh of Turin and they have found that
about 40% of the DNA seems to be of
Indian origin and even the fibers seem
to have been uh manufactured in the
Indis Valley uh region or the western
Indian region. So it looks like this
shroud was manufactured in India.
And then it ended up in Europe and the
DN. Okay, let's let's see what our
friend Google has to say.
Shroud of Turin.
What's it say? What's the news?
Okay, let's see. India,
what's the news?
A 2026 DNA analysis of the shot of Turin
conducted by University of Padawa
researchers found that nearly 40% on the
human DNA of the Indian human DNA on the
cloth has Indian lineages suggesting
that len was likely manufactured or
sourced from the ancient India in this
valley or wherever else
um South Asia to hell with your South
Asia it's India so researchers used
advanced technology next generation se
sequencing on 1978 sample materials to
identify that near the roughly 38.7 to
40% of the DNA originates from Indian
subcontinent lineages.
The data suggests that the flax on the
woven cloth itself was imported by
Romans from India to the Mediterranean
often linked to the term Hinduin in
historical texts.
Uh the study also identified DNA from
various plants, animals, cats, dogs,
pigs, and other regions indicating the
cloth was exposed to numerous
environments over centuries with 55.6%
of the DNA originating from the near
east and 5.5% from Western Europe. While
this suggests an Indian origin for the
material, researchers caution that the
contamination shows the cloth was
handled by diverse populations
throughout history, etc., etc., etc.
Okay.
So the material was of Indian origin. It
doesn't and the study doesn't suggest
that that this shroud was actually used
to to wrap the body of Shri of Shri
Jesus Christ, Mr. Christ. Um and it
doesn't suggest that if Mr. Christ did
exist then he was of Indian origin.
Nothing like that. The material is of
Indian origin. Okay.
Lalita Ananta says big fan of you. Thank
you so much sir or ma'am. listening
listening to your ask shows offline for
the past two years unlearning and
learning many things. Thank you very
much for everything you're doing and for
educating us. Thank you so much for your
very kind and generous comment. Thank
you so much. I really appreciate it and
you are very welcome indeed. Thank you.
Prashant Panor says will it make sense
for the US to use Pakistan for an
invasion? Maybe. Maybe.
Because if we look at the map, the map
tells us half the story, more than half
the story. See,
it's an option the US will consider.
Look here, we have our region. You have
Iran over here. And east of Iran, you
have Afghanistan and Pakistan. Pakistan
shares a pretty large border with with
Iran. Uh the Balojasthan region which is
split between Pakistan and and Persia
and Iran, right?
So um and very close to the uh Pakistan
border roughly about 100 kilometers or
so you're the you're the big port of
Chabahar.
So if the Americans want to make a move
on Chabahar and Kodarak they could
perhaps activate Pakistani troops or
whatever and have this happen. The
question is if they do this will they be
able to hold on to these boards?
Possible if Pakistan gets involved
directly in the matter possible
potentially or maybe not. We'll have to
see. But see, if the Americans want to
take uh take some island like for
example Kirk Island, it's almost
impossible to take it because the
Americans can't transit the straight of
Hormos without getting destroyed.
So it actually makes more sense to
perhaps go after Chavahar or something.
But maybe I'm wrong, maybe I'm right.
We'll see about that. So the US could,
you know, at some point in time activate
Pakistan and use Pakistan against Iran.
Pakistan is is is a mercenary nation.
They will do whatever their master tells
them to do as long as there is something
in it for them.
Pratush Paul says what
if and when EU cave into Trump's threats
and join the war and in response Russia
and China join to what will or should be
India's response. Okay.
So let's say Trump keeps threatening the
Europeans and forces them to join the
war against Iran. Okay. So let's say
hypothetically the Europeans send uh
troops and they send fighter planes and
perhaps ships to the region. Well, that
is obviously something that will augment
America's the American strike
capabilities against Iran and that will
be bad news for Iran potentially, right?
More pressure on on Iran and Iran is now
long no longer fighting a seven eight
front war. It's fighting a 12 13 15
front war. That's how it becomes. So in
that case it's possible that Russia and
China may get involved directly. It may
it may also mean that Russia makes some
very drastic moves in potentially in
Ukraine. Many things could happen as a
consequence of this. So let's say
European nations get involved, Russia
and China also gets involved get
involved in this war. Maybe Pakistan
also gets involved in the war. What
should India's response be? India's
response should be we stay out of this
war. This is not our war.
We are a neutral neighbor of Iran. We
have not started the war and we will not
participate in the war. It is not our
business. It's not our concern. And we
should simply say that we urge restraint
and we urge everybody to stop fighting
and and negotiate and find a peaceful
solution. That's all we should do.
Nothing more. But we should be prepared
at all times for any Pakistani potential
Pakistani treachery or any other thing.
Yours classically says, "Will Iran
actually cut under sea data cables?"
Well, it depends on how badly Iran is
being uh is being hit by the Americans
and Israelis. At some point in time,
Iran may do that. Yeah. If the Americans
and Israelis keep on hitting Iranian
power generating stations,
um oil reservoirs, universities,
schools, cities, whatever. At some point
in time, Iran will say, "Okay, we'll do
this, too. So it depends on how badly
they are provoked by the Americans in
Israelis. Yeah, they they may actually
do it.
P Shukla says, "Namaste Rig, thank you."
Namaste. US has been number one
superpower for about 40 years now. 40
years. Yeah, 40 years. Okay. Since the
collapse of the USSR, um 40 years
36 35 35 or so years. Okay. Uh don't you
think it's be that had it been another
nation world may be much worse I know
the US is bad too especially for bat but
probably the best wikal world had well
that's ifs and buts let's say let's say
the USSR had won the cold war do you
think the world would be so much worse
than what it is under US hgemony I'm not
sure let's say in world war II it's
Germany that won hypothetically you
think there'll be there would have been
much worse than the Americans.
I don't know about that.
I don't know about that. I think all
hedgeims are alike.
They're all alike in different ways.
So in India, we we have this great love
for the Anglo, right? We were under
British occupation for two two and a
half centuries. We are very comfortable
with the Anglo culture in their
language. And that's why we see
something of us in them somehow.
Yeah. We understand them. We we we like
their cinema. We like their movies. We
like their TV series. We like their
social media. We understand them. We
feel like we are part of the same world.
That sort of thing. But if it was
Russia, if it was somebody else, then it
would it would be a different language.
It would be very alien to us. So we
don't feel comfortable.
But that's not the case in my opinion.
Doesn't m matter what language an
oppressor speaks.
operators are all pretty much the same.
Okay. So, I don't think it would have
been it would have made much of a
difference if it was the USSR that had
actually won the cold war or if it was
Germany that was ruling the world. I
don't think it would have made much of a
difference.
For example,
800 years ago, the Mongols rampaged
across the world.
Uh
in the 13th century, Chingghis Khan
smashed Persia to bits, didn't he? Not
Persia, but the Quarasmian Empire. Shah
Muhammad II who had been very cruel to
Chistan's trade envoys. So in response,
Chingistan smashed and obliterated the
Quarasbian Empire which
ruled over Persia. The Quarasbian Empire
was a Turk Empire.
So initially when the Mongols rampaged
across the region, they would have
looked incredibly cruel and completely
alien to the Persians.
But once the Mongols conquered the
place, they turned out to be actually
very good rulers,
right? Despite being so strange and
alien to the Persians. So it's not like,
you know, it makes much of a difference
who the who the hon is. Yeah. If it is
Timur,
it's a disaster. If it is Chingis, well,
he was not that bad of a ruler. He was
actually a pretty benevolent ruler. So,
it depends. I I don't think if it was
Russia instead of the US, it would have
been much worse.
Pinhaar says, if Iran acquires nuclear
weapons, what is the possibility that it
will remain a Chinese vasal or will Iran
itself be in the superpower race? No.
Iran will be in the stable sovereign
nations list.
There are six only six genuinely
sovereign nations in the world. Which
are these genuinely sovereign nations?
The US, Russia, China,
India, Israel, and Iran. That's six.
These are the only genuinely sovereign
nations in the world. Iran is not
anyone's vasal right now. It is fighting
multiple nations, very powerful nations
all alone. The only assistance it's
getting from China and Russia is
satellite imagery and uh satellite
positioning systems. And Russia and
China are helping Iran because of their
own uh you know because it it serves
their their interests. So it's Iran is
no one's vasal
and if Iran acquires nuclear weapons
then its u sovereignty will become
stable because then nobody will want to
mess with Iran especially after seeing
the the ballistic missile and drone
capabilities Iran has once they acquire
nuclear weapons nobody will want to mess
with them so Iran will be a major
regional power maybe a great power
see without a massive economy you can't
be considered to be a great power but a
major regional power it will be it won't
be a superpower any anywhere close to
being a superpower but a major regional
power okay Somalia Paul says fan for the
last four years thank you so much thank
you for opening the eyes also you know I
was checking about who is the owner of
the Fed they have hidden the fact
first of all thank you so much thank you
so much you're very welcome and yes it's
interesting to go and uh go down the
rabbit hole and try to uncover who
actually owns the Federal Reserve Bank
of the United States and you'll just go
deeper and deeper into the rabbit hole
and you'll keep going in circles and you
won't find who actually owns it. That's
how it is. The whole thing is structured
in the US. So you have a privatelyowned
bank that actually runs the economy of
the US and owns the economy of the US
and you don't know who owns this private
bank, who the major shareholders are. So
the US is actually it's actually owned.
It's a privately owned nation and we
don't know who the who the owners are.
That's the situation, isn't it?
Incredible.
D Kat says, "I am afraid of the census.
It may embolden Hindu phobes.
See
the census, it's a statistical,
it's a it's a statistical exercise,
right? It's about collecting data and
then presenting the findings to the
nation.
And obviously things will change, right?
uh demography demographics will have
changed since 2011.
Religious demographics may have changed.
The percentage uh of certain
populations, religious groups may have
changed
and and certain the population of
certain religious groups may have
decreased, some may have increased and
so on. Some may be hidden away and they
may still be misporting what they really
are and so on so forth. So I'm not sure
how it will embolden Hindu folks. I'm
not able to understand how it could be
the case
and I I don't know why you're afraid of
the census. I think it is very important
that we get the census done so that we
know what the current officially
recorded situation is. What's the actual
population of the country? What's the
population distribution? What are the
demographics like? It's important that
we know the the facts about our country.
So I think it's a good thing even if it
may potentially scare you. It is always
better to face the truth than to hide
from it.
Abida Singh says is a is Donald Trump a
blessing in disguise for the world just
like Ra Rahul Gandhi is for the BJP.
Okay. No comments about Indian politics.
Is Donald Trump a blessing in disguise
for the world? See Donald Trump has
started this war. Okay. uh at the behest
of Israel it looks like and the longer
this war goes on
the more painful it's going to be for
much of the world for Australia for
Japan for India for the European nations
for Africa it's going to be painful for
everybody
so I'm not sure how it's a blessing
at least in the short term
long term if it ends up uh weakening the
US and um you uh causing the the
withdrawal of of U of the United States
from West Asia. Well, that in the long
run if if this happens, it may be a good
thing for uh nations like India and Iran
also for China etc. It may be good thing
it may be a good thing for the whole
world you know that this the hedgeimonyy
is is declining. So long-term it may
perhaps overall longterm may be a good
thing but shortterm it's going to cause
a lot of pain. Yeah.
Aman Patania says DNA result of short of
Turan says that Jesus might have 40%
Indian DNA. Is that news correct? What's
your thoughts? So I just took a look at
uh what the the Google AI is saying. I
haven't opened an actual research paper
but what the AI says is that
approximately 40% of the total DNA that
was u studied on a small portion of the
sample about 40% of the DNA was of
Indian origin
and the results show they indicate that
the material
was of Indian origin the fibers of the
cloth were of Indian origin
okay
the DNA does not say that the blood or
whatever may be on the sh of Turin was
that of Mr. Christ of Mr. Jesus.
There is no evidence that this this was
on the body of Mr. Jesus. Okay?
It's it's it's a story that's come along
all this time, but there is no evidence
that Mr. Jesus was was wrapped in this
cloth. No evidence whatsoever.
So, we don't even know if Mr. Jesus
actually existed. And secondly, if he
existed, we don't know that he that we
have no evidence that he was wrapped in
this shroud.
And this 40% DNA, it's a it's related to
see they they they found DNA samples of
uh
of cats, dogs, pigs and so many other
things. But 40% of it is of Indian
origin, which seems to indicate that the
fibers
the fibers of the cloth are of Indian
origin. Maybe western India, the Indis
Valley region, that sort of thing. So it
does not indicate anything. It the
result doesn't say that Mr. Jesus was of
Indian origin. Nothing like that.
Okay.
Yashaswini
Kmini Yashwini Kini says, "Hello sir,
how do you think we as a country can
develop civic sense in our country?"
It's very simple. It's very easy to
develop civic sense. The government
needs to guarantee
that if somebody breaks the rules,
there's going to be a guaranteed
punishment every single time. Every
single time somebody spits on the
street,
that person should be guaranteed a heavy
fine.
Okay? And every time if you spit, if
you're in this habit of spitting and you
spat five times yesterday and the the
fine is 500 rupees per spit per per
incident, then then if you spat five
times on the on the street yesterday and
today you have a fine of 2,500 rupees
and if if you keep doing it and you keep
getting fined, then you're going to
stop.
So if the punishment is guaranteed,
then people will have the incentive to
stop doing this. That's how the
Singaporeans change things. They imposed
heavy fines for things like public
urination, public spitting and whatever
else, jaywalking, whatever. So,
initially Singapore was a third world
nation with very low standards. But
within 20 years, everything had changed.
Everything was transformed. It's all
about the government enforcing the
rules. In India, we have all kinds of
rules and laws on paper, but nothing is
enforced. Nothing is implemented. And
that's why people do whatever they want.
People have to be trained the way we
train children.
And the same Indians when they go to
other countries, they are the most well-
behaved people. They will never spit on
a street. They will never do any of
those things. Right? Because there you
have proper enforcement. So Indians are
by nature a law-abiding people. But then
there is no enforcement of law and there
are no consequences. People do whatever
the hell they want. So it's very simple.
You can keep lecturing people the way
you can keep lecturing children.
See, you can lecture children for hours
and hours and hours. It'll go in through
one year, go out from the other ear.
Instead of lecturing, if you give
guaranteed punishment for misbehavior,
the behavior will change very rapidly.
Lecturing people and say we need to have
better standards and better citizens
will make no difference. Enforce the
laws, guarantee punishment.
which means that our authorities start
to do what they are being paid to do.
Okay, that's what needs to happen.
Empty box says what leverage Israel has
with the US. Looks like Israel is ruling
the US. I don't know what leverage the
the Israelis have with the US. People
say maybe there's something to do with
the Epstein files. Remember the Epstein
files just uh a few weeks ago it was all
over the news. Now people have
completely forgotten it because of this
war.
So um maybe there are big secrets hidden
away in the Epstein files. I mean from
whatever little I saw on social media it
was disgusting and sickening and maybe
very very powerful people uh they are
compromised in the Epstein files. Okay.
And it is alleged that Epstein had links
with Israel. So maybe Israel has all the
all the evidence about various powerful
people in various um in various roles in
the US government potentially. Yeah. Or
possibly. So that's one speculation and
maybe there's some other leverage also
perhaps I don't know it's possible.
Sesh says post war if the US focuses
west and a multipolar south emerges
shouldn't we prioritize Iran Russia oil
pipeline by taking P
we another obsession with P by taking P
or Southeast Asia trade control forget
about P right now Indians forget about P
for now
okay
if the US focuses west and a multipar
south no multipolar south will emerge
What? See what is a multipart south like
a multiparter south means you have
nations like India and is and and
Indonesia and Malaysia
and Vietnam and Iran and Saudi Arabia
and these are all more or less equal
nations and China and North Korea
all these nations are all independent
and sovereign and are all reasonably
powerful in their own in their own right
that's a multipolar south that is not
going to
in the global south. Now if if the US
moves out of West Asia, we're going to
have India, Iran and China
as the powerful nations.
So it's a tripolar south and I and India
and Iran have no enemity of any kind as
such. But China will not want a
multipolar global south. They will they
will want a unipolar global south. So
anyway, forget about the multipolar
angle. If if the US moves out of West
Asia, uh we should buy Iranian and
Russian oil for sure. We don't need to
take P for that. The Americans will not
give up P. They will not give up
Pakistan.
If we if we take it, well and good, but
I don't see it happening soon. I hope
I'm completely wrong. I hope I'm
completely mistaken about that. So, what
we should do is we should simply buy
Iranian oil through oil tankers from the
state of Hormos. Takes like 3 4 days to
come. What's the big deal?
Push says Qatar
Qatar gave the biggest bribe to Trump.
Saudi invested the most in the USA and
got the biggest hit on their land. How
must they have felt? It's it's actually
if you if you put yourself in the shoes
of Qatar and Saudi Arabia, it's it's
painful. It's tragic, isn't it? The
government of Qatar gave an entire
gigantic aircraft as as a as a gift as a
bribe to Trump
and Trump did nothing to protect Qatar
when the war happened. Saudi Arabia has
has bought tens maybe hundreds of
billions worth of American weapons.
Right?
So they have invested and they've bought
American treasury bonds and God knows
what. They've invested a lot in the US
and when the war happens, Saudi Arabia
is hit. The Americans had promised that
we are, you know, we are we are
installing these military bases on your
soil to protect your territory from the
Iranians. But when the war happened,
there was no protection.
The American bases themselves were
destroyed by the Iranians. And every
nation in the Gulf got the impression
that the Americans were more interested
in
in protecting Israel than the Gulf
nations. Yeah. So they will I guarantee
you they will have this strong sense of
betrayal right now that the Americans
have lied to them. They've betrayed
them. They've used them.
And these military bases were more about
controlling those nations, the Gulf
nations, than than for protecting the
Gulf nations.
Abhishek Patil says, "If the US controls
nuclear weapons of Pakistan, why did
India agree to a ceasefire with
Pakistan? What's the real reason behind
the ceasefire?" The real reason
potentially is Trump blackmailing India
and ordering India to stop the war.
Otherwise, I will impose 3 million
different kinds of sanctions and tariffs
on you.
The US can destroy an economy by doing
that. Right?
So whatever the government of India
says, okay, we have to say that for
diplomatic purposes,
uh, but most likely it is Trump's arm
twisting tactics that most likely stop
the war. Most likely because we we hit
some very valuable US assets in
Pakistan. For example, one of the
valuable US assets in Pakistan is the
nuclear weapons. Okay, American nuclear
weapons which most likely are are
handled only by Americans. Pakistanis
are not even allowed near those nuclear
weapons. There are some military bases
where the Pakistanis are not allowed.
Only Americans are are allowed.
Then there is the F-16s that the
Americans have sold to the Pakistanis.
Those F-16s, each of those F-16 fighter
planes,
it is babysat.
There are babysitters for it. These are
American babysitters, American
technicians and American personnel who
babysit every single F-16 and never let
the aircraft out of their sight. So if
India destroyed a number of F-16s in
Nurhan air base or whatever, there would
have been American personnel there
who would also have been hit
by the Indian missiles.
So once that happens, Trump will
immediately pick up the fall the phone
and uh and demand that India stops the
war.
Right? I think Trump did not imagine
that India will start doing so much
damage to Pakistan so rapidly.
I mean within a matter of a few hours,
India hit 11 Pakistani air bases
and if the war had continued another 48
hours, Pakistan would have been
essentially
destroyed militarily at least. So that's
why the Americans that's why Trump
um insisted demanded threatened
he demanded a a stop of the war
immediately
and afterwards Mr. Modi gave an gave a
live address to the nation. You could
see his anger. So you could see the
anger in his face at the time. So I
think that's what happened.
Matt Blackbeard says, "Why are Russians
being cozy with Pakistan and offering
them discounted oil? Also, Iran is
refusing Pakistan's mediation and
calling India to mediate."
Look, oil is not a strategic asset.
Okay? Uh if you are an oil exporter, you
will export it to everybody. The
Russians, for example, okay, they export
uranium to the United States.
Okay. They also export rocket engines to
the United States. Now, I think it's
stopped now, but even after the Ukraine
war, Russia was exporting uranium and
rocket engines to the United States. The
US is Russia's number one enemy, right?
So, it's about money. Russia needs
money. So, it will sell these things
even to the US. And when it comes to
oil, it's not a strategic asset, right?
It's not some sensitive thing. So,
they'll sell it to Pakistan. What's the
big deal? I don't see that being Russia
being cozy with Pakistan. It's simply
selling oil.
I mean India and China are not on good
terms, very good terms. But China still
sends sells things to us. We we also
sell things to China. So this is
business. This is nothing nothing to do
with strategic interests. Uh Iran is
refusing Pakistan's mediation because
Iran knows Pakistan's treacherous
nature.
Okay. India Iran knows that Pakistan is
an American vasal. A couple of years
ago, Iran and Pakistan had a very brief
border conflict and they fired missiles
at each other's territory and Iran
accused Pakistan of doing crossber
terrorism in Iran's territory. So Iran
doesn't like Pakistan. Iran is not a fan
of Pakistan. Iran does not trust
Pakistan. So Pakistan says Sar will
mediate then Iran will say go to hell.
Right. Um
yeah. So
has Iran asked for India to mediate? I'm
not sure. Let's let's fact check that. I
am not aware of that having happened.
Maybe I'm not aware. Let's see.
Iran India mediation
um
mediation mediation mediation
has India asked has Iran
has Iran asked India to mediate in the
war?
No. Yeah, they have. Okay, let's see.
Iranian government sources and
representatives have expressed that
India is the trusted friend and welcomed
its potential role in mediating to
reduce tensions in the ongoing West Asia
conflict with some officials stating
that India could be an effective
positive mediator as per Indian media
reports. Da da da da. Okay. Um
Okay. So whatever look I am not a big
fan of India mediating in all these
matters. This is not our conflict. If we
going to mediate in the war what do we
gain out of it? Okay potentially we
could help end the war but there is no
guarantee of it. I think India should
stay out of this matter. Indians you
know a lot of Indians are they they
hanker after prestige and status. You
know we mediated the end of the war.
Stay out of this matters and the
Americans don't want India as a
mediator. Okay. Trump doesn't want India
as a mediator. So, um it's all right.
Katos Aryasi says is difference of Iran
and Pakistan despite Islamification,
Iran proudly admires its pre-Islamic
heritage and calls Arabs and other
invaders as barbarians. I think that's
the main difference between Iran and
Pakistan. See,
um, Iran is a roughly, you see, about,
if you look at the past 3,000 years of
Iran's history, it's been ruled by at
least 25 dynasties and empires, okay?
starting from the Medians to the
Aeminids to the you know
Macedonians and Salucids and
Parththeians and Sassanids
and Rashidon Umayad
um Abbasid
and so on and so forth caliphate
caliphate and then then the Mongols then
the Turks that theids then the Seljuks
the Safavidids
and the Haku moons for a bit 7 8 9 years
or whatever it was then by the Turks
again Nadasha and then by the Kajar
dynasty again Turk and then the Pahelis
who were British puppets and American
puppets and so on. So long long history
of Iran of all these ups and downs and
they've had certain very catastrophic
periods of time. The one one of the
major catastrophes was for Iran was
Alexander's destruction of Persia.
That's number one. The second major
catastrophe was the Arabic invasion and
occupation of Iran and the destruction
of Iran's traditional religious uh
religion and culture. Okay, that's the
second most devastating second
devastating thing. The third devastating
thing was the Mongol conquest of the
Quoras Empire which included Iran. And
it was not the fault of the Persians. It
was the fault of the godamned sha of
Qurasma idiot person and his cowardly
son.
But somehow Iran has always maintained
it has always retained its language and
it has actually exported its
architecture and art and music and
cuisine and standards to the Islamic
world. So Iran has essentially despite
having forced to become an Islamic
nation, it has exported non-religious
aspects of culture throughout the
Islamic world and the Persian standards
became the glo the global Islamic
standards. So even in India, the Muggal
Empire, the Muggal dynasty, they adopted
Persian standards and Persian uh ways of
doing things and all. So Persia has
somehow en ensured that its its culture
endures in some shape or form through
the language through the architecture
through various other things
right and uh in the 20th century when
you had uh Razash Sha who was the puppet
the British puppet who ruled Persia he
was not very fond of Islam
and he made it a point to emphasize
Persia's pre-Islamic culture
as one of the civilizational foundations
of of Iran, of Persia, right? Um, and
the Persian people are proud are
they they they they are rightfully proud
of their long-standing uh, you know,
history, long-standing civilization and
culture and history despite having lost
their religion to foreigners.
Uh
so if you the thing about if you compare
Persia and Pakistan is this if you
remove Islam hypothetically okay
completely hypothetically from Persia
you still have Persian culture and the
Persian language but Persian culture
which is distinctly Persian it did not
come from anywhere else. If you remove
Islam hypothetically from Turkey, they
still have Turk Turkish culture.
If you remove Islam from Pakistan, what
do they have? They're just Indians,
right? So the Pakistanis are deeply
they they they
want to be anything except anything
other than Indians, right? They are very
deeply ashamed of their forefathers
having having been Hindus and all that.
So Iran is proud of its pre-Islamic
heritage and Pakistan is ashamed of its
pre-Islamic heritage. That's the biggest
difference between the two uh nations
says and Pakistan calls Turk invaders
like Kilji Baba as heroes disavows its
Hindu past. So Iran acts to preserve its
sovereign identity against Turks and
Arabs. Exactly. Exactly. That's the
deal, right? The the Pakistanis they
glorify
the Kilgis and the and and the Gaznis
and the the Gaznavis and the Goris and
Babar and Orurange.
All these barbarians who brutalize their
own ancestors, they are glorified today,
right? And they want to distance
themselves from their actual past which
is their their Indian and Hindu past.
So yeah, that's the difference between
Pakistan and Iran
really. Now Miss Patel says US Israel
hard power falling. Iran are so
courageous. Well, you've got to admire
what Iran is doing. We in India worry
about fighting a two-front war, two and
a half front war. Iran is fighting
simultaneously against five, six, seven
countries, eight countries, nine
countries, I don't know. US, Israel,
um technically Kuwait,
Iraq, Jordan,
Saudi Arabia,
Qatar, Bahrain,
UAE,
that's nine. Oman 10. It's fighting a
10-front war. Even Azarbaijan 11 front
war.
Yeah.
Iran is fighting an 11front war right
now
and
well they clearly locally have more hard
power and firepower than the US and
Israel. Clearly they do. So yeah, you
got to admire what the Iranians are
accomplishing here. You don't have to
agree with their their government or
whatever, but what they are doing on a
military front from a in a professional
manner. If you are a military
professional, you you you are bound to
admire what they're doing and respect
what they're doing. Okay. Pad a pagadi
akai.
Yeah. Thank you so much. Thank you very
much. A
really now Patel says Iran is showing
Iran are showing how it's done. The
empire can be shaken. Yes. And why is
Iran able to show how it's done? Because
they have prepared really really well.
They've put in the hard hard work.
They've done their homework
and they've analyzed their opponent's
strengths and weaknesses and their own
strengths and weaknesses really really
well and they've taken all the measures
necessary to ensure that they they come
out um successful. So it's really
tremendous
uh professionalism and you got to going
to respect what they're doing.
Shatabish Shatabish says stakes for
China are are highest with Iran compared
to low sustainable during Synindur and
Venezuel Venezuela. That's why it's
providing the best technology to Iran.
What Ukraine is to the US, Iran is to
China. That is a proxy war. No, Iran is
not a Chinese proxy.
Ukraine is an American proxy. Yes, Iran
is a sovereign nation. It is fighting on
its own. China is providing satellite
imagery and perhaps the BU positioning
system and China is doing this because
if Iran falls it's a disaster for China.
So China is doing it doing this for its
own interests.
Okay, not because Iran is a Chinese
proxy or a Chinese vasal. Okay. So yes
stakes
the stakes are very high for China when
it comes to Iran. They they can't afford
to see Iran fall to the US and to
Israel. If Iran is taken out, it's going
to be an absolute disaster for China
because they'll be left with Russia
only.
Um, and yeah, it's providing high
quality satellite uh positioning uh data
services to Iran and the satellite uh
imagery uh that it is providing to Iran.
Yes.
Fields strong maners. You've said that a
civilization is a net exporter of
culture and
not importer. You've also said that US
is an empire not a civilization. Means a
civilization is not necessary to
dominate culture. Since America is
dominating now, can one differentiate
burger vocism rap versus yog? What?
Since America is dominating now, can one
differentiate burger, vocism, rap versus
yogan future? I have no idea what any of
that means. See what have I said? What
have I said? A civil, there are multiple
characteristics. There's a whole set of
characteristics that a civilization has.
One of those characteristics is that a
civilization is a net exporter of
culture, not an absorber or importer of
culture. Okay. I've also said that the
US is an empire, not a civilization
because the US does not have many of the
characteristics that a civilization has.
Does it mean that a civilization is not
necessary to to dominate culture? No,
it's you don't have to be a civilization
to dominate culture.
You don't have to be a civilization to
export culture.
You don't need to be a civilization to
be the dominant culture in the world.
The Romans were not a civilization. They
were an empire. And yet they exported
their culture as long as they were
dominant. The whole of Europe started
speaking Latin. Today if you look at the
text over here, what script is this? We
are speaking this is the English
language but the script is Latin.
If you read Norwegian, it's the Latin
script with slight modifications. If you
read German, it's the Latin script with
slight modifications. If you read
French, it's the Latin script with
slight modifications.
If you read Italian, same things to all
across Europe, apart from Russia, apart
from Georgia and Armenia
and and Greece. You have the Latin
script. That's how much Rome exported
its culture despite not being a
civilization, despite being an empire.
Okay. So, that's what I can tell you. I
don't know about burger vocism and rap
yoga. I have no idea about that. I'm not
I'm not sure what you're asking. So, not
clear.
Dirj Kamat says if the 0.5 front
Abrahamic supremacist supremacists know
that Hindu population is reduced they
will get emboldened further. The census
should be kept secret. No it doesn't
work like that. See in a nation like
India the census has to be done
periodically and the results have to be
shared with the entire population.
That's how it is done in India. India is
a democracy isn't it?
And I'm pretty sure the Hindu population
will have reduced. I'm pretty sure.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure because the way
things are going, the Hindu population
is is going to reduce. So I think it is
important that we find out exactly what
the situation is and so that people
don't keep living in La La Land. I think
it's important we know what's happening.
It should not be kept secret. It should
be publicized so that everyone
understands what has been happening and
how much the governments of the past few
years or decades have slipped up very
badly.
in in safeguarding our civilization.
MTB rider. Thank you very much. MTB
rider. Ah, that's a that's a bike. Is it
two-heer bicycle? MTB. Okay.
International reporter says, "Have you
did you watch the 4,000 crude Ramayana
teaser? Your thoughts? I haven't seen
it. I am not going to watch it. I'm not
going to watch the teaser. I'm not going
to watch the movie." Okay. I'm not
watching it. I'm not going to waste my
precious time watching
what's his name
as as Lord Ra as Sri Ram. Come on, I'm
not watching it.
Okay. MTB writer says, "Will Hindu
Muslim population change in the future?
These things are see population and
demographics are never static."
Okay, they're dynamic. Keep changing ups
and downs and so on so forth. So I'm
pretty sure the percentage of the Hindu
Muslim population in India will change
in the future. It will change. Pretty
sure.
Okay.
Sarishi Chakra says, "Were the Europeans
always so tall or after colonization?"
See
when the Europeans first started uh
arriving in the Americas
uh after see this guy Columbus
discovered he thought he discovered
India but he had discovered the Bahamas.
So when he discovered the Americas in
1492 after that the Spaniards started
arriving in the Americas greedy
Spaniards looking for golden slaves and
all that. Then the then the French and
the English started arriving
on the um on the east coast of the
United States starting from Florida,
Virginia, etc. All those regions and
eventually went all the way up north.
And whenever they met the natives, they
were shocked to see how healthy and how
tall the natives were compared to the
Europeans. The Europeans were short,
unhealthy, extremely dirty, unhygienic,
etc. And the natives of the Americas
were tall, very well constructed bodies
and extremely healthy. So the native
Americans were on average significantly
taller than the Europeans.
But then European the European diet
changed because of the industrial
revolution and the plenty plentiful
production of food and everything else.
And that's why when you have a better
diet, your body also changes.
Um even the Chinese the past few decades
they have also grown taller. Right? The
Dutch weren't tall 200 years ago. Today
they are the tallest people in the
world. It all depends on the diet.
Okay. Lakshadep Bhutak says Iran US war
is to stop growth of India China.
The what's the objective of the Iran of
the war against Iran? Right. You have
two nations who are attacking Iran. One
is Israel, the other is the US. Both
seem to have different objectives. For
the US, it's about controlling Iran's
oil because Iran's oil accounts for
about 15 to 20% of China's oil imports.
If you stop that, it's a massive blow to
China.
So for the US, it's all about oil. Oil.
Oil. Why did they go off to Venezuela?
Because Venezuela has a big the world's
largest reserves, proven reserves of
oil. That oil is heavy SAR oil or
whatever, but it's still oil, right? So
the Americans have taken that over. Now
they want to take over Iran's oil and
that's why they've done the war also
because Israel dragged them into the war
and Israel has a different set of
objectives. Israel wants to be the only
hijab in the region and the only thing
standing in their way is Iran and also
Iran says that Israel doesn't have the
right to exist and so on. So obviously
Israel can't accept that. So So it's not
about
India as much as China for the US. Of
course, the US also has this this policy
of containing India. Right now they have
this containment policy against India
which they are implementing. But mainly
it's about China and about securing
taking control of Iran's oil for the US.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Sometimes I feel
like the same powers are controlling
both the US and Russia and also Israel
and India and we are all just actors in
this grand game."
Well, who knows? Maybe it's true what
you're saying. I have no idea. I can
only discuss what I can see. There's a
lot that I'm aware that we are unable to
see. There's a lot that's hidden and
shrouded behind secrecy.
So yeah, sometimes one can potentially
get that sort of feeling. What can I
say?
Ankita Kachab good evening ma'am
question how is Judaism different from
Zionism are not no not all Jews are
Zionist question mark what's your
opinion on project Israel of the US
looks like we have been shown or told
only one side of the story by the
mainstream media please shed some light
Zionism versus Judaism Judaism is the
religion which is about 3,000 years old
it's the religion of the Jewish people
which originally was a polytheistic
religion and then slowly morphed into a
monotheistic religion with one god one
and only one god which is Yahweh.
Uh and they had a variety of other gods.
I forget the names of their gods because
they're hard to pronounce and hard to
remember but the main god is Yahweh
today. I mean the only god. So it's a
monotheistic religion but it used to be
polytheistic. So Judaism is there. It's
got a 3,000 year year old history.
Zionism
as far as I understand it is political
it's it's the political demand for see
in the
after the Jews were expelled from Israel
by the by the Romans
they spread all across Europe and other
parts of the world and for roughly 2,000
years they were out of their homeland
which is present day Israel that region
Judea
So in the 18th in the 19th century and
the early 20th century there was a
demand for a nation for the Jews and
that is Zionism.
Okay. The the the the
desire and demand of the Jews to have
their own homeland and a powerful and
strong and secure homeland that is
Zionism. So they have achieved their
objective of having their own nation
Israel. It's been recreated after a gap
of I don't know about 2,000 or so years.
So now that the nation exists, what is
Zionism? It still exists, right? Zionism
still exists. I am not very clear about
what Zionism is. So let's let's do one
thing. I will also educate myself. What
is Zionism in the present day context?
What is Zionism?
Let's see. A nationalistic nationalist
political and ideological movement that
emerged in the 19th century Europe
advocating for the creation and later
support of a Jewish state in Palestine.
Yeah. So its core goal is to ensure the
safety, sovereignty and
self-determination of the Jews in
response to historical persecution and
systematic systemic anti-semitism. Okay.
So that's what it is.
Yeah.
So it's achieved its objective of having
of creating a Jewish state and now it's
about uh safety and sovereignty and
self-determination of the Jewish people.
So yeah, it's about having a strong
Israel. That is what Zionism is. And
there are various different kinds of
Jewish denominations and different kinds
of viewpoints, political viewpoints
among the Jewish people. And I'm sure
that there are plenty of Jews who are
not Zionist. Yeah.
Right. So, okay. Now, what is my opinion
on Project Israel of the US? I am not
aware of Project Israel of the US. What
is that? Project Israel of the US? I am
not aware of it. Let's see.
Project Israel of the US.
What is that?
I'm not aware of any project. Are you
talking about a greater Israel project?
Are you talking about something else?
So there is no project Israel that the
US has the US uh the US
offers unconditional support to Israel
in whatever Israel does. Is that what
you're referring to as project Israel?
I'm not 100% certain. If you're asking
me why does the US support Israel always
unconditionally no matter what happens
it's because the Jewish diaspora is
extremely powerful and influential in
the US in the 1920s or whatever about
almost 30% of New York's population was
Jewish and many of them were very
wealthy and very powerful very connected
and so on and the Jewish diaspora is
very well tight is very tightly tightly
knit very well connected very
influential very powerful in the US A
lot of very highranking politicians and
officials in the US are are Jewish and
the Jews always support Israel no matter
what. It's not they're not like Indians
that once you become a US citizen you
forget about India and and you know
don't support India. It's not like that
with the Jews. The Jews no matter what
nationality they have they will always
support Israel. So that that's why uh
there is this very big uh Jewish
constituency not very big but very
powerful Jewish constituency in the US
and since they're at all various levels
of the US government including some of
the highest levels uh that's why the US
always and and they're in both parties
the Republicans and Democrats equally.
So it's not like if the Republicans come
to power it's pro-Israel. If the
Democrats come to power it's not
pro-Israel. No doesn't matter who is in
power it's always pro-Israel. That's why
the US is so pro-Israel.
Um, yeah, that's what I can tell you.
Okay.
Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Do you think the
US will pull out of NATO soon?" I don't
think it's going to happen soon. Okay.
Uh, let me show you why. Um, where is
that? Okay.
Uh, so look at this. I'll show you.
It won't happen anytime soon because of
this.
See,
this is a piece of news from 2023,
December 14. The US Congress approves a
bill barring any president from
unilaterally withdrawing from NATO.
Okay,
so any US president who wants to
withdraw from NATO will need the
approval of Congress and due process.
And see once again over here this is a
tweet from 2023 by Marco Rubio who is
now the secretary of state of the US
and he says says that no US president
should be allow should be able to
withdraw from NATO without Senate
approval.
Thankful to my colleagues in Congress
thankful my colleagues in Congress
passed this bipartisan measure. So he
was part of the passing of this bill
Marco Rubio. So this makes it difficult
for a US president to just unilaterally
quickly withdraw from NATO. It's not
possible. They will need Senate approval
and that will not be that easy. Okay.
Rock says Russia, China, US all have
expansion targets. As India becomes
stronger, would where should we expand
or shall we keep a defensive mindset?
Um,
Russia allegedly has expansionist
targets.
Um, Russia has shown no such tendencies.
Russia from a military perspective is
way more powerful than India. But it's
not trying to conquer other nations
territories.
It's not.
A few a couple of decades ago, Vladimir
Putin had actually officially formally
applied for
Russia becoming a member of NATO, which
means that he had no intention of
expanding anywhere. He wanted a peaceful
coexistence with other European nations.
Of course, the US denied this request,
right? And see, Russia is fighting
Ukraine not as an expansionist project,
but because they have no choice because
they can't allow NATO to encroach into
Ukraine. So Russia doesn't have any
expansionist targets. China is an
expansionist Germanic nation. The US
also is that that's what they've done.
So as India becomes stronger, should we
also have expansionist tendencies? No, I
don't think so.
We should seek to liberate Tibet from
Chinese occupation
and we should seek to perhaps long-term
reunify the subcontinent. Maybe it
should be a 50 or 100 year project. can
do can do it now right now with that
sort of population radicalized
population. So I think that's what we
should do and right now we should not
focus we should not try we should ensure
that we don't get embroiled in any
military confrontation with anybody the
next 20 years we should keep our head
down and work on becoming a major
economy and a very powerful nation
that's all
Pratep Kumar Roy says did you watch the
two views I haven't seen it yet I
haven't seen it but I look forward to
watching it very soon honest human says
when can we expect your next podcast
with de talks with Adi Your expressions
are too interesting and fun to notice
notice. Love your content anyways or
always. Thank you very much. Um I
suppose it'll happen sooner or later. We
don't like plan for that. If something
interesting happens,
uh I may have a podcast with with uh
Adi. We'll see about that. It's it's
never something we we plan that you know
we'll do it once a month or once in two
weeks or whatever. It just happens on
the fly. So we'll see. We'll see. And
thank you so much. Thank you.
MTB writer says will Muslims surpass
Hindus in India's future when I have no
idea. I don't discuss this religious
matters. Okay. I don't discuss India's
internal matters. I discuss geopolitics,
history and science. This is there are
plenty of channels which discuss these
Hindu Muslim issues. This channel is not
for that. I'm very sorry if you think it
is if you got the impression that I I
discuss this but I don't discuss these
matters. I
Yeah. Okay. Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Do
you think the people who run this world
are not very wise? I mean, they
understand money and power but not life
so much. What do you think?" I think the
people who who run the world
do it out of a sense of self-interest
and they see people as statistics, not
as as humans.
I think Joseph Stal Stalin said it very
well, right? One death is a tragedy. A
million deaths is a statistic,
right?
So when you are a person who is ruling a
very large nation, you can't allow
yourself to be to be swayed by emotions
that so many people died or so whatever.
You have to look at it statistically
from a numerical perspective and look at
the long-term large scale macro interest
of the nation. Of course, you should try
and minimize human human suffering, but
overall you have to look at the
long-term and large scale thing. So when
people are let's say ruling or running
the world they will do it that way and
they will have their own agendas. They
may be very powerful people. They may
also be very wise. But they their wisdom
is going to serve them, not us. And they
will of course understand money and
power. And when you understand money and
power, when when you get that that kind
of power, uh it it it corrupts a lot of
people. It intoxicates a lot of people.
And then you stop valuing the the the
the well-being and happiness of uh other
people. I suppose
Ankita G says, "Ah Singh wants to know,
have you watched Durand? What's your
view?" I haven't watched it yet,
unfortunately.
Um,
yeah. So, I don't have any views or
reviews right now. I look forward to
watching it soon. I certainly will watch
it, but I haven't come come around to
watching it yet.
E Republic of India says, "If the US
invades Iran and asks Pakistan for
support like air like air bases or a
second front, could Pakistan indeed
instead escalate with India to avoid
backing a USIsrael effort and to satisfy
domestic opinion?"
Well, what does Pakistan gain from it?
Pakistan gets a beating again from
India,
right?
If the US asks Pakistan for support and
Pakistan starts fighting with India,
it's going to get a bloody nose again
from India. India is militarily
significantly superior to Pakistan.
So, it's going to have its Nurhan and
Bolari and other bases again smashed up
by India. How does that serve Pakistan's
interests?
But what if it agrees to what the
Americans are saying and starts fighting
with Iran and then the Iranians destroy
their bases. So I think if the Americans
try to drag Pakistan into this war with
war with Iran, it's going to be heads I
win tail tails you lose for Pakistan. If
it's fight if it fights Iran, it's going
to get smashed up by Iran.
And uh if it fights India, which doesn't
make any sense, it's going to get bashed
up by India also.
So no good options for Pakistan.
Okay. Lakshed Bhutak says you are a
great person and role model. Carry on.
Thank you so very much Luxib G. Thank
you so much.
Anves Sha Anveves Shauna has become a
new member of the of the channel. Thank
you so much Anvesha G and welcome to the
channel's membership. Thank you so much
and Anvesha G. Thank you very much
indeed. Thank you.
Okay. Pratip Kumar Roy says Malok is
actually adrac and the sacrificial fire
is anamele. The same fire that is used
to initiate brahmos
and also freemasons. Some say I don't
know. Okay. I don't have any
understanding or knowledge of these
matters. I haven't studied the Abrahamic
religions and Judaism is extremely
obscure from my perspective. I don't
know much about it. Uh I am aware of
various Bal gods. I am vaguely aware of
the existence of this god called Malik.
I don't know what Andra Malik and
Anameal is.
Brahmos and Freemasons. I have
absolutely no idea about this. So I I
can't comment about this because I don't
know anything about this.
G Praaran has become a new member. Thank
you so much for becoming a member and
welcome to the channel's membership.
Thank you so much.
Anonymous says, "Any tips on time
management? I'm 18 years old, male, big
fan." Thank you very much. You're most
welcome. Thank you very much. Time
management. Tips on time management.
See,
um what would I would say about this is
uh when you're doing time management,
when you're planning for let's say the
next day or the next week, don't make a
big long list of tasks that you have to
accomplish.
Okay,
in a day you should have only two or
three major tasks,
not more than that. If you have like 15
different tasks, it's going to it's
going to burn you out. And a lot of
those tasks are going to be tasks that
don't really take you forward in the
right direction.
So, you should have maximum three tasks,
major tasks in a day.
And uh you should uh
prioritize you should know at what time
in the day your energy is the highest
and that's that's the time in which you
should do the most important and most
mentally demanding or physically
demanding tasks.
Uh and yeah so so remember the 80/20
rule right 80% of your results come from
20% of the work that you do. So identify
what is that 20% of the work that you do
that produces 80% of the results and
focus on that. Okay. Right. So that's
what I can say in very brief. It's a
very big and rich and deep topic but
yeah. All right. All the best. Do well
then and thank you. Rich Blaze says, "Is
Trump a way for the US deep state to
carry out dirty stuff so that the next
person in power can get away by just
staying by just saying this that that
was Trump?" Maybe. Maybe.
See, Trump is the right guy for the
right time for the deep state.
See, we we know very well that the
United States doesn't really need a
president to to to
be governed.
From 2020 to 24, you had Biden who was
the president. Biden was not mentally
there, right? He was not capable of
taking care of himself. Forget about the
country. And Kamala Harris was not
competent enough to be the vice
president. So, who was running running
the country? Somebody was and it went
fine.
So, the US president really doesn't
matter. Okay?
And someone like Trump is useful to to
shake up the world and make a mess of
the world and change the whole system
and destabilize the world. So see the US
understood that the so-called
rules-based world order that they had
constructed over the past 70 or so
years, it was now serving China and
Russia and India more than it was
serving the US. And that's why they
decided to tear up this world order and
create a new one. And for that sort of
work, you need someone like Trump. And
that's why they got Trump in into the
position that he is right now. And let's
see how Trump does does go goes about
things. He's he's right now making a
mess of the situation in Iran and if he
doesn't do well then the next guy can
come in and say you know what let's it's
all Trump's fault and let's let's move
forward from there from wherever we
wherever we are. So yeah. Yeah.
Pratib Kumar Royce says, "Your views
about basketball as a sport. Full body
workout far better than cricket and also
football probably. It is a it's a super
sport.
I feel like basketball is a very fast
game
and it's a pretty fun game to play. A
very very fast and yeah full body
workout for sure. Yes, both arms, legs,
back, core, shoulders,
everything. Yes, it's a full body
workout and uh yeah, I think it's a
great sport.
uh better than cricket certainly as a
full body workout. You don't get that in
cricket. You either you're standing and
batting and you sprint a little bit or
you're fielding waiting for the ball to
come to you or if you're a spinner then
what? So yeah, definitely better than
cricket from from a full body workout
perspective. Football
football is a pretty active game, a
pretty active sport. If you play a
90-minute game of football, then you may
end up running 10 km as as an individual
player unless you substituted. So that
also is good but football doesn't have
the upper arm workout that basketball
gives you. So I think basketball overall
is superior from that perspective. Alvin
Rodriguez says it's a question of our
future. Do we need a new minister in
charge of the department of space in
India and how can private sector
contribute?
I don't know who is the minister in
charge of the department of space. I
don't think uh there is a minister in
charge of space. I don't know who it
comes under. Does it come under the
prime minister's office? I'm not sure.
Look, you can create a new ministry for
this,
but if there is,
see, what we need is a long-term 50-year
plan of where we want to be in 50 years.
By 2100, where do we want to be in the
space race? What do we want to have
accomplished by 2100? We need to start
with that long-term vision and then we
can move back, you know, reverse
engineer it as to what should we do in
the next five or 10 years, 5 to 10
years. So you always start with a big
vision but for 2100 and then work
backwards. Ask yourself that if I want
to achieve this big these big goals by
2100 what should I have accomplished by
2050 and if I want to ac accomplish that
by 2050 then what do I need to
accomplish by 2030? So you move step by
step like that and you make the plans
and then you have a ministry that
implements it and makes makes sure that
this happens and you have to ensure that
you get the right budget and everything
else that the uh department of space
needs. That's how it's supposed to be
done. Now simply putting a minister is
not going to solve any of the issues.
You're going to have to completely
revamp the whole the entire way we we're
doing this right now. It looks like
space is also something that okay we
have it. It's nice to have let them keep
doing something once in a while. That's
the kind of approach and attitude we
have right now towards space. So the
entire approach, attitude, vision, uh
ambition, all of that needs to change
and if we don't have a vision, it looks
like first of all. So we need to have a
clear vision and goal for 2100 and 2050
and then we can start working forward.
That's what needs to happen. Private
sector contribute. Yes, certainly the
private sector can contribute. We should
encourage the priv private sector to
start building rockets or at least
rocket components, spaceship and space
spacecraft components, uh motors and so
much more. Yeah, we certainly can have
the private sector contribute
significantly if we
make it easy for the private sector to
to operate in this uh sector.
Aid Singh says happy Hanuman Janti.
Thank you very much. Happy Hanuman Janti
to you and to all the viewers. Happy
Hanuman Janti.
Pratep Kumar Roy says Brahma Samaj I
meant not Brahos. Oh okay. Okay okay
okay. Brahmo Samaj. Interesting.
Interesting. All right.
Shini KNS says Trump's posture on
hormones can weaken petro dollar a lot.
Yes it can. If the US
doesn't achieve its objectives in this
war, if the out of West Asia because its
because its military bases are gone,
then Iran becomes the predominant
hedgeman in the region and it can force
all the Gulf nations
to trans to do oil transactions in non
US dollar currencies that can very badly
weaken the petro dollar system. Yes.
So if Trump is a genius, he should
somehow find a way to win this war.
Otherwise, it's going to impact the
petro dollar significantly if Iran
succeeds in surviving this war and
coming out uh as the overall winner
HR devices. Is there a possibility of
some Muslims? No, I will not take Hindu
Muslim questions. I'm not I'm not taking
Hindu Muslim questions. I don't do it as
a as a matter of policy on this channel.
We don't discuss Hindu, Muslim and all
that stuff. There are many channels that
do that. This is not the channel for
that. Okay? I'm very sorry.
Push SA says, "Okay, as a new member."
Well, thank you very much, Push, and and
welcome to this channel's membership.
Thank you so much. And that is it. That
brings me to the end of today's live
stream. All right. Thank you so much
everybody.
Um and I look forward to seeing you all
this weekend. The next live stream will
be uh today is Thursday, Friday, day of
tomorrow, Saturday night, India time.
So, thank you so much. Keep uh keep
learning, keep asking questions, keep
raising your standards. And I say I
shall see you in the next live stream
very soon. Until then, take care. Good
day, good night. See you soon. Bye-bye
for now.